<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०६ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/06/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०६ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/06/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SPECIAL PRELIMINARY RITES OF THE NEW-MOON SACRIFICE.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/06/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/06/4/</guid>
      <description>01 When Indra had hurled the thunderbolt at Vr̥tra, thinking himself to be the weaker, and fearing lest he had not brought him down, he concealed himself and went to the farthest distances 1. Now the gods knew that Vr̥tra had been slain and that Indra had concealed himself. 02 Agni of the deities, Hiraṇyastūpa 2 of the R̥shis, and the Br̥hatī of the metres, set about searching for him. Agni discovered him and stayed with him (as a guest) that (day and) night.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE TWO BUTTER-PORTIONS (ÂGYABHÂGA) TO AGNI AND SOMA.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/06/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/06/1/</guid>
      <description>01 Now the Seasons were desirous to have a share in the sacrifice among the gods, and said, &amp;lsquo;Let us share in the sacrifice! Do not exclude us from the sacrifice! Let us have a share in the sacrifice!&amp;rsquo; 02 The gods, however, did not approve of this. The gods not approving, the Seasons went to the Asuras, the malignant, spiteful enemies of the gods. 03 Those (Asuras) then throve in such a manner that they (the gods) heard of it; for even while the foremost (of the Asuras) were still ploughing and sowing, those behind them were already engaged in reaping and threshing: indeed even without tilling the plants ripened forthwith for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/06/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/06/2/</guid>
      <description>01 Verily, by means of the sacrifice the gods made that conquest (of the world of heaven). When they had conquered, they said, &amp;lsquo;How may this (celestial region) be made unattainable by men?&amp;rsquo; They then sipped the sap of the sacrifice, as bees would suck out honey; and having drained the sacrifice and effaced the traces of it with the (sacrificial) post 1, they concealed themselves: and because they effaced (ayopayan, viz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/06/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/06/3/</guid>
      <description>01 Tvashṭr̥ had a three-headed, six-eyed son. He had three mouths; and because he was thus shaped, his name was Viśvarūpa (&amp;lsquo;All-shape&amp;rsquo;). 02 One of his mouths was Soma-drinking, one spirit-drinking, and one for other kinds of food. Indra hated him and cut off those heads of his. 03 Now from the one which was Soma-drinking, a hazel-cock (francoline partridge) sprang forth; whence the latter is of brownish colour, for king Soma is brown.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
