<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०६ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/06/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०६ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/06/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/06/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/06/1/</guid>
      <description>01 He lays down the Nākasads (firmament-seated bricks): the firmament-seated ones, assuredly, are the gods. In this (layer) that whole fire-altar becomes completed, and therein these (bricks are) the firmament (nāka), the world of heaven: it is therein that the gods seated themselves; and inasmuch as the gods seated themselves on that firmament, in the world of heaven, the gods are the firmament-seated. And in like manner does the Sacrificer, when he lays down these (bricks), now seat himself on that firmament, in the world of heaven.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/06/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/06/2/</guid>
      <description>01 He lays down Cḥandasyās 1 (bricks pertaining to the metres). Completed now was the entire Agni (fire-altar). He now wished for distinction 2; for, indeed, heretofore he was not equal thereto, that he should sustain distinction; whence people here say even to this day, &amp;lsquo;This one is not equal to sustain distinction, either in regard to kingship or to headmanship.&amp;rsquo; The gods bestowed on him this distinction, these Cḥandasyās; for the metres (Cḥandas) are cattle, and cattle are food, and (a position of) distinction is food.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/06/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/06/3/</guid>
      <description>01 He lays down the Gārhapatya. For the gods, having obtained this much, thought they had succeeded. They spake, &amp;lsquo;Whereby have we succeeded in this?&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;By means of the Gārhapatya,&amp;rsquo; they said; &amp;lsquo;for, after building the Gārhapatya 1 and mounting thereon, we saw the first layer, from the first (we saw) the second, from the second the third, from the third the fourth, from the fourth the fifth, and from the fifth this one.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
