<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०२ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/02/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०२ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/02/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>THE PREPARATION OF THE ALTAR.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/02/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/02/3/</guid>
      <description>01 Fourfold, namely, was Agni (fire) at first. Now that Agni whom they at first chose for the office of Hotr̥ priest passed away. He also whom they chose the second time passed away. He also whom they chose the third time passed away 1. Thereupon the one who still constitutes the fire in our own time, concealed himself from fear. He entered into the waters. Him the gods discovered and brought forcibly away from the waters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/02/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/02/1/</guid>
      <description>01 Now the one (viz. the Āgnīdhra) puts the potsherds on (the Gārhapatya fire); the other (viz. the Adhvaryu) the two mill-stones (on the black antelope skin): these two acts are done simultaneously. The reason why they are done simultaneously (is this): 02 The head of this sacrifice is (represented by) the rice-cake 1: for those potsherds (kapāla), no doubt, are to this (rice-cake) what the skull bones (kapāla) are to the head, and the ground rice is nothing else than the brain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/02/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/02/2/</guid>
      <description>01 He pours (the ground rice) into that which contains the strainers&amp;ndash;viz. into a dish (pātrī) on which he has laid the two strainers&amp;ndash;with the text (Vāj. S. I, 21): &amp;lsquo;At the impulse of the divine Savitr̥ I pour thee out, with the arms of the Aśvins, with the hands of Pūshan!&amp;rsquo; The import of this formula is the same (as before, I, 1, 2, 17). 02 He now sits down somewhere inside the altar (vedi) 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/02/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/02/4/</guid>
      <description>01 When Indra hurled the thunderbolt at Vr̥tra, that hurled one became fourfold. Of (three parts of) it the wooden sword (sphya) represents one-third or thereabouts, the sacrificial post one-third or thereabouts, and the chariot one-third or thereabouts. That piece, moreover, with which he struck him, was broken off (śr̥); and on falling down it became an arrow (śara): hence the designation arrow, because it was broken off. And in this way the thunderbolt became fourfold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/02/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/02/5/</guid>
      <description>01 The gods and the Asuras, both of them sprung from Prajāpati, were contending for superiority. Then the gods were worsted, and the Asuras thought: &amp;lsquo;To us alone assuredly belongs this world! 02 They thereupon said: &amp;lsquo;Well then, let us divide this world between us; and having divided it, let us subsist thereon!&amp;rsquo; They accordingly set about dividing it with ox-hides from west to east. 03 The gods then heard of this, and said: &amp;lsquo;The Asuras are actually dividing this earth: come, let us go to where the Asuras are dividing it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
