<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०७ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/07/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०७ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/07/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>THE ANIMAL SACRIFICExa0[^fn_365].</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/07/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/07/1/</guid>
      <description>01 He performs the animal sacrifice. Now the animal sacrifice means cattle: thus, when he performs the animal sacrifice (paśubandha, the binding of the animal), it is in order that he may be possessed of cattle. Let him perform it at his home, thinking, &amp;lsquo;I will bind (attach) cattle to my home.&amp;rsquo; Let him perform it in the season of abundant fodder, thinking, &amp;lsquo;I will bind to myself cattle in a season of abundant fodder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/07/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/07/2/</guid>
      <description>01 Now there is one animal sacrifice of the Haviryajña order 1, and another of the order of the Soma-sacrifice. Of the Haviryajña order is that at which he (the Adhvaryu) brings him fast-food 2, leads water forward 3, and pours out a jarful of water 4, and at which (the Sacrificer) strides the Vishṇu-strides 5; and of the order of the Soma-sacrifice is that (animal sacrifice) at which these (rites) are not performed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/07/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/07/3/</guid>
      <description>01 Such a (sacrificial stake) as has much substance 1 is not auspicious to cattle, whence he who desires to have cattle should not make such a one his sacrificial stake: but such a one as is of little hardness is auspicious to cattle, whence he who desires to have cattle should make such a one his sacrificial stake. 02 And such a one as, while being crooked, has a top like a spit, is called &amp;lsquo;kapotī 2&amp;rsquo;; and whoever makes such a one his sacrificial stake certainly goes to yonder world before his full measure of life: therefore let no one wishing for long life make such a one his sacrificial stake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/07/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/07/4/</guid>
      <description>01 Now, when he who is about to perform an animal sacrifice makes a stake one cubit long, he thereby gains this (terrestrial) world; and when (he makes) one two cubits long, he thereby gains the air-world; and when be makes one three cubits long, he thereby gains the heavens; and when he makes one four cubits long, he thereby gains the regions. But, indeed, that sacrificial stake of the (ordinary) animal sacrifice is either three or four cubits long, and one that is above that belongs to the Soma-sacrifice.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
