<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०३ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/06/03/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०३ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/06/03/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>THE SÂVITRA LIBATIONS.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/06/03/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/06/03/1/</guid>
      <description>01 The gods then said, &amp;lsquo;Meditate ye!&amp;rsquo; whereby doubtless they meant to say, &amp;lsquo;Seek ye a layer!&amp;rsquo; Whilst they were meditating, Savitr̥ saw those Sāvitra (formulas); and inasmuch as Savitr̥ saw them, they are called Sāvitra. He offered that eightfold-taken libation; and when he had offered it, he saw this eightfold-appointed Ashāḍḥā 1, which had been created aforetime. 02 Now when they said, &amp;lsquo;Meditate ye!&amp;rsquo; they doubtless meant to say, &amp;lsquo;Seek ye a layer!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE SEARCH AND DIGGING FOR AGNI (THE LUMP OF CLAY).</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/06/03/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/06/03/2/</guid>
      <description>01 The spade is still in his hand, when he addresses the beasts. For when the gods at that time were about to search (for Agni) in these (animals) they placed their vigour in front; and in like manner does this one, now that he is about to search in these (animals), place his vigour in front.
02 He addresses the horse, with (Vāj. S. XI, 12), &amp;lsquo;Most speedily 1, O courser, run hither,&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;what is swift, that is speedy, and what is swifter than swift, that is most speedy;&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;along the widest range,&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;the widest range doubtless is this (earth): thus, &amp;lsquo;along this wide range;&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;in the sky is thy highest home, in the air thy navel, upon earth thy womb:&amp;rsquo; he thus makes it to be those deities, Agni, Vāyu, and Āditya (the sun), and thus lays vigour into the horse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/06/03/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/06/03/3/</guid>
      <description>01 Those fires have been kindled (afresh); and they (the priests and sacrificer) betake themselves to the lump of clay 1;&amp;ndash;those fires doubtless are these worlds: when they are kindled, then they are these worlds. For formerly the gods were seeking this sacred rite outside of these worlds; and when he fetches the lump of clay after passing by those fires, he is seeking him (Agni) outside of these worlds. 02 They go eastwards; for the east is Agni&amp;rsquo;s region: he thus seeks him in his own region, finds him in his own region.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
