<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०१ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/01/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०१ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/01/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>THE MYSTERY OF AGNI, THE FIRE-ALTAR.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/01/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/01/1/</guid>
      <description>01 In the first place that Agni (the Fire-altar), the year, is built 1; thereafter the Great Litany (mahad uktham) is recited 2. When Prajāpati became relaxed, the vital fluid flowed upwards 3. 02 Now, that Prajāpati who became relaxed is the year; and those joints of his which became relaxed are the days and nights. 03 And that Prajāpati who became relaxed is this very Fire-altar which here is built; and those joints of his, the days and nights, which became relaxed are no other than the bricks;&amp;ndash;thus, when he lays down these (in the layers of the altar), he thereby restores to him those joints of his, the days and nights, which had become relaxed: and thus it is even in this (building of the altar) that this Yajus is built up 4 and secured (for Prajāpati).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/01/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/01/2/</guid>
      <description>01 Prajāpati was desirous of gaining these worlds. He saw this bird-like body, the Fire-altar: he fashioned it, and thereby gained this (terrestrial) world. He saw a second bird-like body, the (chant of the) Great Rite 1: he fashioned it, and thereby gained the air. He saw a third bird-like body, the Great Litany 1: he fashioned it, and thereby gained the sky.
02 This built Fire-altar, doubtless, is this (terrestrial) world, the Great Rite the air, and the Great Litany the sky: all these, the Fire-altar, the Great Rite, and the Great Litany, one ought therefore to undertake together, for these worlds were created together; and as to why the Fire-altar is built first, it is because of these worlds this (terrestrial) one was created first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/01/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/01/3/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/01/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/01/4/</guid>
      <description>01 Now, at the beginning, Prajāpati was (composed of) both these, the mortal and the immortal&amp;ndash;his vital airs alone were immortal, his body mortal: by this sacrificial performance, and by this order of proceeding, he made his body uniformly undecaying and immortal. And in like manner is the Sacrificer (composed of) both the mortal and the immortal&amp;ndash;his vital airs alone are immortal, his body mortal: by this sacrificial performance, and by this order of proceeding, he makes his body uniformly undecaying and immortal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/01/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/01/5/</guid>
      <description>01 This built fire-altar, in truth, (includes) all these sacrifices:&amp;ndash;when he slaughters an animal victim, that is the Agnyādheya (establishment of the sacred fires) 1; when he collects (the materials for) the fire-pan, that constitutes the oblations of the Agnyādheya; when he performs the initiation, that is the Agnihotra; and when the initiated puts two logs on (the fire) 2, these are the two oblations of the Agnihotra.
02 He puts them on in the evening and in the morning, for in the evening and in the morning the Agnihotra oblations are offered;&amp;ndash;with one and the same formula, for with one and the same formula the two Agnihotra oblations are offered 3.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
