<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०१ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/01/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०१ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/01/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>THE FULL AND NEW-MOON SACRIFICE.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/01/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/01/1/</guid>
      <description>01 Verily, Prajāpati, the Sacrifice, is the Year: the night of new moon is its gate, and the moon itself is the bolt of the gate. 02 And when one lays down the two fires at new moon 1,&amp;ndash;even as one would enter a stronghold by the gate, when the gate is open, and would thence reach the world of heaven, so it is when one lays down the fires at new moon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/01/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/01/2/</guid>
      <description>01 Now when they spread (and perform) the sacrifice, they kill it; and when they press out king Soma, they kill him; and when they &amp;lsquo;quiet&amp;rsquo; and cut up the victim, they kill it,&amp;ndash;it is by means of the mortar and pestle, and by the two mill-stones that they kill the Haviryajña (grain-offering). 02 And having killed the sacrifice, he pours it, as seed, into the fire as its womb, for, indeed, the fire is the womb of the sacrifice, from out of it it is produced: let him therefore perform those ten oblations 1 for which the Vashaṭ is uttered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/01/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/01/3/</guid>
      <description>01 When he has performed the Full-moon sacrifice, he prepares an additional (cake) for Indra Vimr̥dh (the repeller of scorners), and offers it in accordance with the procedure of an ishṭi 1; and when he has performed the New-moon sacrifice, he prepares an additional rice-pap for Aditi 2, and offers it in accordance with the procedure of an ishṭi. 02 And as to why, after performing the Full-moon sacrifice, he prepares (a cake) for Indra Vimr̥dh, it is because Indra is the deity of the sacrifice; but the chief oblation of the Full-moon sacrifice belongs to Agni and Soma, and nothing is offered there with the formula &amp;lsquo;To Indra (I offer) thee!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/01/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/01/4/</guid>
      <description>01 Now, some people enter upon the fast 1 when they (still) see (the moon, on the fourteenth day of the half-month), thinking, &amp;lsquo;To-morrow he will not rise,&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;either on account of clouds or not having ascertained properly, they enter upon the fast, and (in the morning) he rises over him. Now if he (the moon) should rise on (the material for) the oblation being not yet taken out, then that approved (procedure is followed) and the same fasting-observance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/01/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/01/5/</guid>
      <description>01 He observes the fast thinking, &amp;lsquo;To-day is the day of new moon 1;&amp;rsquo; and then that (moon) is seen in the west. But, indeed, he (the moon) is that heavenly dog: he watches the Sacrificer&amp;rsquo;s cattle (to seize them), and that would not be good for cattle if amends were not made to them 2; and through fear of that &amp;lsquo;down-coming moon 3,&amp;rsquo; as they think him to be,&amp;ndash;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/01/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/01/6/</guid>
      <description>01 Verily, in the beginning this (universe) was water, nothing but a sea of water. The waters desired, &amp;lsquo;How can we be reproduced?&amp;rsquo; They toiled and performed fervid devotions 1, when they were becoming heated, a golden egg was produced. The year, indeed, was not then in existence: this golden egg floated about for as long as the space of a year. 02 In a year&amp;rsquo;s time a man, this Prajāpati, was produced therefrom; and hence a woman, a cow, or a mare brings forth within the space of a year; for Prajāpati was born in a year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/01/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/01/7/</guid>
      <description>01 Now there, on the occasion of the entering on the fast, it is said 1, &amp;lsquo;If he does not eat, he becomes consecrated to the Fathers 2; and if he does eat he eats whilst passing over the gods;&amp;rsquo; and, in this respect, they lay down the rule, &amp;lsquo;Let him therefore eat what grows in the forest.&amp;rsquo;
02 If he eats cultivated plants he eats the sacrificial essence of the offering-cake; and if he eats forest plants he eats the essence of the barhis 3; and if he eats aught of trees he eats the essence of the fuel (for the sacrificial fire); and if he drinks milk he consumes the essence of the Sānnāyya 4; and if he drinks water he consumes the essence of the lustral waters 5; and if he eats nothing he becomes consecrated to the Fathers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/01/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/01/8/</guid>
      <description>01 Now, the gods and the Asuras, both of them sprung from Prajāpati, once strove together. Then the Asuras, even through arrogance, thinking, &amp;lsquo;Unto whom, forsooth, should we make offering?&amp;rsquo; went on offering into their own mouths. They came to naught, even through arrogance: wherefore let no one be arrogant, for verily arrogance is the cause of ruin 1. 02 But the gods went on offering unto one another. Prajāpati gave himself up to them, and the sacrifice became theirs; for, indeed, the sacrifice is the food of the gods.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
