<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०५ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/05/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०५ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/05/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>THE ADÂBHYA-GRAHA.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/05/9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/05/9/</guid>
      <description>01 Now, the Aṁśu (cup of Soma) 1, indeed, is no other than Prajāpati; and it is the body of this (sacrifice), for Prajāpati, indeed, is the body. And the Adābhya 2 (cup of Soma) is no other than speech. When he draws the Aṁśu-cup, and then the Adābhya-cup, he thereby constructs the body of this (sacrifice) and then establishes that speech therein. 02 And, indeed, the Aṁśu is also the mind, and the Adābhya speech; and the Aṁśu is the out-breathing, and the Adābhya the up-breathing; and the Aṁśu is the eye, and the Adābhya the ear: these two cups they draw for the sake of wholeness and completeness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE SATÂTIRÂTRAM, OR SACRIFICIAL SESSION OF A HUNDRED ATIRÂTRA-SACRIFICES.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/05/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/05/5/</guid>
      <description>01 Now, when the gods were passing upwards to the world of heaven, the Asuras enveloped them in darkness. They spake, &amp;lsquo;Verily, by nothing else save a sacrificial session is there any way of dispelling this (darkness): well, then, let us perform a sacrificial session!&amp;rsquo; 02 They entered upon a sacrificial session of a hundred Agnishṭoma (days), and dispelled the darkness as far as one may see whilst sitting; and in like manner did they, by (a session of) a hundred Ukthya (days), dispel the darkness as far as one may see whilst standing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE SEASONAL SACRIFICES (Kâturmâsya).</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/05/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/05/2/</guid>
      <description>01 By means of the Seasonal sacrifices, Prajāpati fashioned for himself a body. The sacrificial food for the Vaiśvadeva 1 sacrifice he made to be this right arm of his; the oblation to Agni thereof this thumb; that to Soma this (fore-finger); and that to Savitr̥ this (middle finger).
02 That cake (to Savitr̥), doubtless, is the largest, and hence this (middle finger) is the largest of these (fingers). That (oblation) to Sarasvatī is this (third) finger; and that to Pūshan this (little finger).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE STUDY OF THE VEDA.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/05/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/05/6/</guid>
      <description>01 There are five great sacrifices, and they, indeed, are great sacrificial sessions,&amp;ndash;to wit, the sacrifice to beings, the sacrifice to men, the sacrifice to the Fathers, the sacrifice to the gods, and the sacrifice to the Brahman. 02 Day by day one should offer an oblation to beings: thus he performs that sacrifice to beings. Day by day one should offer (presents to guests) up to the cupful of water 1: thus he performs that sacrifice to men.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE UPANAYANA, OR INITIATION OF THE BRÂHMANICAL STUDENTxa0[^fn_283].</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/05/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/05/4/</guid>
      <description>01 He says, &amp;lsquo;I have come for Brahmacarya 1:&amp;rsquo; he thereby reports himself to the Brahman. He says, &amp;lsquo;Let me be a Brahmacārin (student):&amp;rsquo; he thereby makes himself over to the Brahman. He (the teacher) then says, &amp;lsquo;What (ka) is thy name?&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;now Ka is Prajāpati: he thus initiates him after making him one belonging to Prajāpati. 02 He then takes his (right) hand with, &amp;lsquo;Indra&amp;rsquo;s disciple thou art; Agni is thy teacher, I am thy teacher, O N.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/05/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/05/1/</guid>
      <description>01 The nymph Urvaśī loved Purūravas 1, the son of Iḍā. When she wedded him, she said, &amp;lsquo;Thrice a day shalt thou embrace 2 me; but do not lie with me against my will 3, and let me not see thee naked, for such is the way to behave to us women.&amp;rsquo;
02 She then dwelt with him a long time, and was even with child of him, so long did she dwell with him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/05/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/05/3/</guid>
      <description>01 Śauceya Prācīnayogya came to Uddālaka Āruṇi for a disputation on spiritual matters 1, thinking, &amp;lsquo;I desire to know the Agnihotra.&amp;rsquo; 02 He said, &amp;lsquo;Gautama, what like is thy Agnihotra cow? what like the calf? what like the cow joined by the calf? what like their meeting? what like (the milk) when being milked? what like when it has been milked? what like when brought (from the stable)? what like when put on the fire?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/05/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/05/7/</guid>
      <description>01 Now, then, the praise of the study (of the scriptures). The study and teaching (of the Veda) are a source of pleasure to him, he becomes ready-minded 1, and independent of others, and day by day he acquires wealth. He sleeps peacefully; he is the best physician for himself; and (peculiar) to him are restraint of the senses, delight in the one thing 2, growth of intelligence, fame, and the (task of) perfecting the people 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/05/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/05/8/</guid>
      <description>01 Verily, in the beginning, Prajāpati alone was here. He desired, &amp;lsquo;May I exist, may I be generated.&amp;rsquo; He wearied himself and performed fervid devotions: from him, thus wearied and heated, the three worlds were created&amp;ndash;the earth, the air, and the sky. 02 He heated these three worlds, and from them, thus heated, three lights (jyotis) were produced&amp;ndash;Agni (the fire), he who blows here (Vāyu), and Sūrya (the sun). 03 He heated these three lights, and from them, thus heated, the three Vedas were produced&amp;ndash;the R̥g-veda from Agni, the Yajur-veda from Vāyu, and the Sāma-veda from Sūrya.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
