<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०२ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/02/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०२ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/02/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>HIRANYAVATÎ-ÂHUTI,  OFFERING WITH GOLD; AND HOMAGE TO THE SOMA-COW.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/02/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/02/4/</guid>
      <description>01 Now Soma was in the sky, and the gods were here on earth. The gods desired,&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;Would that Soma came to us: we might sacrifice with him, when come.&amp;rsquo; They created those two illusions, Suparṇī and Kadrū. In the chapter on the hearths (dhishṇya 1) it is set forth how that affair of Suparṇī and Kadrū came to pass. 02 Gāyatrī flew up to Soma for them. While she was carrying him off, the Gandharva Viśvāvasu stole him from her.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE PRÂYANÎYESHTI,  OPENING-SACRIFICE.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/02/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/02/3/</guid>
      <description>01 He prepares the Prāyaṇīya rice-pap for Aditi. Now while the gods were spreading (performing) the sacrifice on this (earth) they excluded her (the earth) from the sacrifice. She thought, &amp;lsquo;How is it that, in spreading the sacrifice on me, they should exclude me from the sacrifice?&amp;rsquo; and confounded their sacrifice: they knew not that sacrifice. 02 They said, &amp;lsquo;How comes it that our sacrifice was confounded, when we spread it on this (earth)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/02/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/02/1/</guid>
      <description>01 South of the Āhavanīya he spreads two black antelope skins on the ground, with the neck parts towards the east: thereon he consecrates him. If there are two (skins), they are an image of these two worlds (heaven and earth), and thus he consecrates him on these two worlds. 02 They are joined (fitted) together along their edge 1, for these two worlds are also, as it were, joined together at their edge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/02/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/02/2/</guid>
      <description>01 He maintains silence; and silently he remains seated till sunset. The reason why he maintains silence is this: 02 By means of the sacrifice the gods gained that supreme authority which they now wield. They spake, &amp;lsquo;How can this (world) of ours be made unattainable to men?&amp;rsquo; They sipped the sap of the sacrifice, even as bees would suck out honey; and having drained the sacrifice and scattered it by means of the sacrificial post, they disappeared: and because they scattered (yopaya, viz.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
