<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०५ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/05/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०५ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/05/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DIFFERENT ARRANGEMENTS OF THE CHANTS OF THE ASVAMEDHA.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/05/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/05/4/</guid>
      <description>01 Now, Indrota Daivāpa Śaunaka once performed this sacrifice for Janamejaya Pārikshita, and by performing it he extinguished all evil-doing, all Brahman-slaughter; and, verily, he who performs the Aśvamedha extinguishes (the guilt incurred by) all evil-doing, all Brahman-slaughter. 02 It is of this, indeed, that the Gāthā (strophe) sings,&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;In Āsandīvat 1, Janamejaya bound for the gods a black-spotted, grain-eating horse, adorned with a golden ornament and with yellow garlands.&amp;rsquo; 03 [There are] those same first two days 2, and a Jyotis 3 Atirātra: therewith (they sacrificed) for Bhīmasena;&amp;ndash;those same first two days, and a Go Atirātra: therewith (they sacrificed) for Ugrasena;&amp;ndash;those same first two days, and an Āyus Atirātra: therewith (they sacrificed) for Śrutasena.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE STOTRAS AND SASTRAS OF THE SOMA-DAYS.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/05/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/05/1/</guid>
      <description>01 Then, on the morrow, there is (used) Gotama&amp;rsquo;s Stoma (form of chanting) successively increasing by four (verses) 1: the Bahishpavamāna thereof is on four, the Ājya (stotras) on eight, the Mādhyandina Pavamāna on twelve, the Pr̥shṭḥa (stotras) on sixteen, the Ārbhava Pavamāna on twenty, and the Agnishṭoma-sāman on twenty-four (verses).
02 Now, some make its Agnishṭoma-sāman a Sāman of four (verses), saying, &amp;lsquo;It is neither an Agnishṭoma, nor an Ukthya 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE VAPÂ-OFFERINGS.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/05/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/05/3/</guid>
      <description>01 Now as to the offering of the omenta. &amp;lsquo;They should proceed with them singly up to the omentum of the Vaiśvadeva (victim) 1; and when the omentum of the Vaiśvadeva has been offered, they should thereupon offer the others,&amp;rsquo; said Satyakāma Jābāla; &amp;lsquo;for, doubtless, the All-Gods (Viśve Devāḥ) are all (sarve) the gods: it is in this way he gratifies them deity after deity.&amp;rsquo; 02 &amp;lsquo;When the omentum of the Aindrāgna (victim) has been offered, they should thereupon offer the others,&amp;rsquo; said the two Saumapa Mānutantavya;&amp;lsquo;for, doubtless, Indra and Agni are all the gods: it is in this way he gratifies them deity after deity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/05/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/05/2/</guid>
      <description>01 Having uttered these two (verses), he pronounces what remains of the Adhrigu. &amp;lsquo;A cloth, an upper cloth, and gold,&amp;rsquo; this is what they spread out for the horse 1: thereon they &amp;lsquo;quiet&amp;rsquo; (slaughter) it. When the victims have been &amp;lsquo;quieted,&amp;rsquo; the (king&amp;rsquo;s) wives come up with water for washing the feet,&amp;ndash;four wives; and a young maiden as the fifth, and four hundred female attendants. 02 When the foot-water is ready, they cause the Mahishī to lie down near the horse, and cover her up with the upper cloth, with &amp;lsquo;In heaven ye envelop yourselves,&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;for that indeed is heaven where they immolate the victim, .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
