<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०८ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/08/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०८ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/08/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>FUNERAL CEREMONIES.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/08/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/08/1/</guid>
      <description>01 They now 1 do what is auspicious for him. They now prepare a burial-place (śmaśāna 2) for him, (to serve him) either as a house or as a monument; for when any one dies, he is a corpse (śava), and for that (corpse) food (anna) is thereby prepared, hence &amp;lsquo;śavanna,&amp;rsquo; for, indeed, &amp;lsquo;śavanna&amp;rsquo; is what is mystically called &amp;lsquo;śmaśāna.&amp;rsquo; But &amp;lsquo;śmaśāḥ&amp;rsquo; also are called the eaters amongst the Fathers, and they, indeed, destroy in yonder world the good deeds of him who has had no sepulchre prepared for him: it is for them that he prepares that food, whence it is &amp;lsquo;śmaśānna,&amp;rsquo; for &amp;lsquo;śmaśānna&amp;rsquo; is what is mystically called &amp;lsquo;śmaśāna.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/08/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/08/2/</guid>
      <description>01 Now, some bank up (the sepulchral mound) after covering up (the site). The gods and the Asuras, both of them sprung from Prajāpati, were contending for (the possession of) this (terrestrial) world. The gods drove out the Asuras, their rivals and enemies, from this world; whence those who are godly people make their sepulchres so as not to be separate (from the earth), whilst those (people) who are of the Asura nature, the Easterns and others, (make their sepulchral mounds) so as to be separated (from the earth), either on a basin 1 or on some such thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/08/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/08/3/</guid>
      <description>01 He then sows (seed) of all (kinds of) herbs: what the all-herb (seed signified) on that occasion 1, that (it does) here. With many (verses 2) he sows that (former seed), with a single one this,&amp;ndash;he thus keeps the divine separate from what belongs to the Fathers,&amp;ndash;with 3.
02 He then pours out that (jarful of bones 4); for this earth is the foundation: on this (earth), as a foundation, he thus establishes him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/08/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/08/4/</guid>
      <description>01 They now fix pegs round it 1,&amp;ndash;a Palāśa (Butea frondosa) one in front,&amp;ndash;for the Palāśa is the Brahman (n.): he thus makes him go to the heavenly world with the Brahman for his leader;&amp;ndash;a Śamī (Prosopis spicigera) one on the left (north corner), in order that there may be peace (śam) for him;&amp;ndash;a Varaṇa (Crataeva Roxburghii) one behind, in order that he may ward off (vāraya) sin from him;&amp;ndash; and a Vr̥tra-peg 2 on the right (south corner) for sin not to pass beyond.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
