<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०६ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/06/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०६ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/06/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>THE ANIMAL SACRIFICExa0[^fn_428] TO AGNI AND SOMA.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/06/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/06/4/</guid>
      <description>01 Being about to cut the sacrificial stake, he offers 1 with a verse addressed to Vishṇu. For the stake belongs to Vishṇu; therefore he offers with a verse addressed to Vishṇu. 02 And again, why he offers with a verse addressed to Vishṇu&amp;ndash;Vishṇu being the sacrifice, he thus approaches the stake by means of the sacrifice: therefore he offers with a verse addressed to Vishṇu. 03 If he offers with the offering-spoon, he offers after taking ghee by four ladlings; and if he offers with the dipping-spoon, he offers after &amp;lsquo;cutting out&amp;rsquo; (some ghee from the pot) with the dipping-spoon,&amp;ndash;with the text (Vāj.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE VAISARGINA OFFERINGS AND LEADING FORWARD OF AGNI AND SOMA.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/06/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/06/3/</guid>
      <description>01 Verily he who consecrates himself, consecrates himself for the sake of this All; for he consecrates himself for the sacrifice, and this All indeed results from 1 the sacrifice; having prepared the sacrifice for which he consecrates himself, he now sets free (or produces) this All. 02 The reason why he performs the Vaisarjina offerings is this. They are called Vaisarjina, because he sets free (vi-sarj) this All; wherefore let him who takes part in the rite 2 touch (the sacrificer) from behind; but if he have to go elsewhere (on business) he need not heed this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/06/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/06/1/</guid>
      <description>01 The Sadas 1 is no other than his (Vishṇu, the sacrifice&amp;rsquo;s) belly; therefore they feed (drink) in the Sadas; for whatever food is eaten here on earth, all that settles down in the belly. And because all the gods sat (sad) in it, therefore it is called sadas: and so do these Brāhmans of every family now sit therein. By way of deity it belongs to Indra.
02 In the middle of it he puts up a (post) of udumbara wood (Ficus Glomerata); for the udumbara means strength and food; now the Sadas being his (Vishṇu&amp;rsquo;s belly), he thereby puts food therein; this is why he puts up an udumbara (post) in the middle of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/06/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/06/2/</guid>
      <description>01 The Dhishṇya-hearths 1, forsooth, are no other than its (the sacrifice&amp;rsquo;s) congeners 2. They have the same marks, and those which have the same marks are congeners; and these, then, are those (corresponding limbs) of its trunk.
02 Now Soma was in heaven, and the gods were here on earth. The gods desired, &amp;lsquo;Would that Soma might come to us; we might sacrifice with him, when come.&amp;rsquo; They produced those two illusions, Suparṇī and Kadrū 3; Suparṇī, forsooth, was Vāc (speech) 4, and Kadrū was this (earth).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
