<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०७ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/07/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०७ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/07/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/07/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/07/1/</guid>
      <description>01 He lays down two Ritavyā (seasonal bricks). The seasonal (bricks) are the same as these seasons: it is the seasons he thereby lays down. And, indeed, the seasonal ones are everything here, for the seasonal ones are the year, and the year is everything here: he thus lays down everything here. And generative power they also are,&amp;ndash;for the seasonal ones are the year, and the year means generative power: it is generative power he thus lays down (or bestows on Agni and the Sacrificer).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/07/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/07/2/</guid>
      <description>01 He then lays down a Lokampr̥ṇā 1 (space-filling brick); the Lokampr̥ṇā, doubtless, is yonder sun, for he fills these worlds: it is thus yonder sun he thereby sets up. He lays down this (Lokampr̥ṇā) in all the (five) layers, for those layers are these (three) worlds 2: he thus places the sun in (all) these worlds, whence he shines for all these worlds.
02 And, again, as to why he lays down a Lokampr̥ṇā,&amp;ndash;the Lokampr̥ṇā, doubtless, is the nobility (or chieftaincy) 3, and these other bricks are the peasants (or clansmen): he thus places the nobility (or chieftain), as the eater, among the peasantry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/07/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/07/3/</guid>
      <description>01 He now throws loose soil (on the layer); for the loose soil means flesh: he thus covers him (Agni) with flesh. [He does so] after having laid down the bricks;&amp;ndash;the bricks are the bone: he thus covers the bone with flesh. 02 He also strews it on (the place where lies) the naturally-perforated (brick), for the naturally-perforated one means vital air, and the loose soil means food: he thus puts food into (the channels of) the vital air.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/07/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/07/4/</guid>
      <description>01 On the (three) naturally-perforated (bricks) he (the Sacrificer) sings sāmans; for the naturally-perforated ones are these (three) worlds; and they are just these (ordinary) stones. The gods, having laid them down, saw them as such: that they were dry stones.
02 They spake, &amp;lsquo;Think ye upon this, how we may lay sap, the means of subsistence, into these worlds!&amp;rsquo; They spake, &amp;lsquo;Meditate ye!&amp;rsquo; whereby, doubtless, they meant to say, &amp;lsquo;Seek ye a layer!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
