<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०९ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/09/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०९ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/09/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>B. THE PRÂTAHSAVANA, OR MORNING-PRESSING.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/09/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/09/4/</guid>
      <description>01 Thereupon they sit down round the two press-boards 1. He (the Adhvaryu) then ties a piece of gold to that (nameless finger). For twofold, verily, is this; there is no third, namely, the truth and the untruth; the gods, forsooth, are the truth, and men are the untruth. And the gold has sprung from Agni&amp;rsquo;s seed: &amp;lsquo;With the truth I will touch the stalks, with the truth I will take hold of Soma,&amp;rsquo; thus he thinks, and therefore he ties a piece of gold to that (ring-finger).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE SOMA FEAST.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/09/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/09/3/</guid>
      <description>01 They (the priests) are wakened (towards morning). Having touched water 1, they proceed together to the Āgnīdhra (fire-house) and take the portions of ghee (for the Savanīya animal offerings). Having taken the portions of ghee, they betake themselves (to the high altar). When they have deposited the ghee,&amp;ndash; 02 He (the Adhvaryu) takes down the king (Soma) 2. Now this (earth) is a safe resting-place, and the birth-place of living beings; it is to this safe resting-place that he now takes him down; he spreads him thereon, produces him therefrom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE VASATÎVARÎ WATER.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/09/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/09/2/</guid>
      <description>01 Now, when the head of the sacrifice (victim) was struck off, its sap, running, entered the waters. It is by that very sap that those waters flow; that very sap is believed to be flowing there 1. 02 And when he goes for the Vasatīvarī water, he fetches that same sap and puts it into the sacrifice, and makes the sacrifice sapful; this is why he goes for the Vasatīvarī water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/09/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/09/1/</guid>
      <description>01 Now Prajāpati (the lord of creatures), having created living beings, felt himself as it were exhausted 1. The creatures turned away from him; the creatures 2 did not abide with him for his joy and food. 02 He thought within him, &amp;lsquo;I have exhausted myself, and the object for which 3 I have created has not been accomplished: my creatures have turned away from me, the creatures have not abode with me for my joy and food.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
