<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०१ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/01/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०१ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/01/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A. THE VÂGAPEYA.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/01/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/01/1/</guid>
      <description>01 Once upon a time the gods and the Asuras, both of them sprung from Prajāpati, strove together. And the Asuras, even through arrogance, thinking, &amp;lsquo;Unto whom, forsooth, should we make offering?&amp;rsquo; went on offering into their own mouths. They came to naught, even through arrogance: wherefore let no one be arrogant, for verily arrogance is the cause 1 of ruin. 02 But the gods went on making offerings unto one another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/01/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/01/2/</guid>
      <description>01 He draws the Aṁśu 1 (graha), just for completeness’ sake, for it is therefor that he draws the Aṁśu. After that he draws those recognised Agnishṭoma cups 2 up to the Āgrayaṇa.
2, 2, He then draws the Pr̥shṭḥyas 3: and whatever the gods (Agni, Indra, and Sūrya) won by them, even that he wins by them.
03 He then draws the Shoḍaśin: and whatever Indra won thereby, even that he (the sacrificer) wins thereby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/01/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/01/3/</guid>
      <description>01 At the Agnishṭoma (Sāman 1) he seizes a (victim) for Agni, for the Agnishṭoma (i.e. &amp;lsquo;Agni&amp;rsquo;s praise 2) is Agni: he thereby wins Agni. For the Ukthas 3 he seizes one for Indra and Agni; for the hymns (uktha) relate to Indra and Agni 4: the hymns he thereby wins. For the Shoḍaśi n he seizes one for Indra; for the Shoḍaśin is Indra: the Shoḍaśin (Indra) he thereby wins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/01/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/01/4/</guid>
      <description>01 At the midday Soma-feast he consecrates (the Sacrificer) by sprinkling; and at the midday Soma-feast they run a race; for, verily, Prajāpati is that sacrifice 1 which is here performed, and from which these creatures have been produced,&amp;ndash;and indeed, they are even now produced after this one: thus he thereby wins Prajāpati in the very centre (of the sacrifice). 02 The Māhendra cup being not yet drawn,&amp;ndash;for that, the Māhendra, is Indra&amp;rsquo;s special (nishkevalya) cup, and so also are his that Nishkevalya-stotra and Nishkevalya-śastra; and the Sacrificer is Indra: thus he consecrates him at his own dwelling-place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/01/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/01/5/</guid>
      <description>01 Now when they run a race, he thereby wins this same (terrestrial) world. And when the Brahman sings a Sāman on the cart-wheel set up on (a post) reaching to his navel, he thereby wins the air-world. And when he erects the sacrificial post, he thereby wins the world of the gods. Hence that threefold performance. 02 The Brahman mounts a cart-wheel, set up on (a post) as high as his navel 1, with (Vāj.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
