<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०१ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/01/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०१ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/01/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>THE BUILDING OF THE SACRED FIRE-ALTAR (continued). THE CONSTRUCTION OF THE FIRST LAYER (continued).</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/01/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/01/1/</guid>
      <description>01 He lays down the Prāṇabhr̥taḥ (breath-holders) 1: now, the Prāṇabhr̥taḥ being&amp;ndash;the vital airs, it is the vital airs he thereby bestows upon (Agni). He lays them down in the first layer;&amp;ndash;that which is the first layer is the forepart (ground-part) of Agni: it is thus in front that he puts (into Agni) the vital airs, whence there are (in creatures) these (orifices of the) vital airs in front.
02 He lays them down by ten and ten, for there are ten vital airs; and even though &amp;rsquo;ten-ten&amp;rsquo; may mean many, times, here they mean only ten.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/01/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/01/2/</guid>
      <description>01 And at the back (western part of the altar), with (Vāj. S. XIII, 56), &amp;lsquo;This one behind, the all-embracer;&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;the all-embracer, doubtless, is yonder sun, for as soon as 1 he rises, all this embracing space comes into existence. And because he speaks of him as (being) &amp;lsquo;behind,&amp;rsquo; therefore one sees him only when he goes towards the back (west). The Sun, indeed, having become the eye, remained behind: it is that form he now bestows (on Agni).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/01/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/01/3/</guid>
      <description>01 As to this they say, &amp;lsquo;What are the vital airs (prāṇa), and what the Prāṇabhr̥taḥ?&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;The vital airs are just the vital airs, and the Prāṇabhr̥taḥ (holders of the vital airs) are the limbs, for the limbs do hold the vital airs. But, indeed, the vital airs are the vital airs, and the Prāṇabhr̥t is food, for food does uphold the vital airs. 02 As to this they say, &amp;lsquo;How do all these (Prāṇabhr̥t-bricks) of him (Agni and the Sacrificer) come to be of Prajāpati&amp;rsquo;s nature?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/01/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/01/4/</guid>
      <description>01 Now some lay down (these bricks) so as to be in contact with the (gold) man, for he is the vital air, and him these (bricks) sustain; and because they sustain (bhr̥) the vital air (prāṇa), therefore they are called &amp;lsquo;Prāṇabhr̥taḥ.&amp;rsquo; Let him not do so: the vital air is indeed the same as that gold man, but this body of his extends to as far here as this fire (altar) has been marked out.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
