<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०५ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/05/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०५ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/05/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CONSTRUCTION OF SHEDS, AND PREPARATION OF PRESSING-PLACE AND HEARTHS (DHISHNYAS).</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/05/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/05/3/</guid>
      <description>01 The sacrifice is a man; it is a man for the reason that a man spreads (prepares) it. In being spread it is made just as large 1 as a man: this is why the sacrifice is a man. 02 The Soma-cart (shed) is no other than his head, and has Vishṇu for its deity 2. And because Soma is therein&amp;ndash;Soma being havis (material for offering) for the gods&amp;ndash;therefore it is called Havirdhāna (receptacle of havis).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PREPARATION OF THE SOMA ALTAR WITH THE HIGH ALTARxa0[^fn_290].</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/05/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/05/1/</guid>
      <description>01 From that post which is the largest on the east side (of the hall) 1 he now strides three steps forwards (to the east), and there drives in a peg,&amp;ndash;this is the intermediate (peg) 2. 02 From that middle peg he strides fifteen steps to the right, and there drives in a peg,&amp;ndash;this is the right hip. 03 From that middle peg he strides fifteen steps northwards, and there drives in a peg,&amp;ndash;this is the left hip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE AGNI-PRANAYANA, OR LEADING FORWARD OF THE FIRExa0[^fn_321] TO THE HIGH ALTAR.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/05/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/05/2/</guid>
      <description>01 They put fire-wood on (the Āhavanīya fire), and prepare the underlayer (of gravel 1). He (the Adhvaryu) puts the butter on (the Gārhapatya to melt), and cleans both the dipping-spoon and the offering-spoon. Having then clarified the ghee, he ladles five times thereof (into the offering-spoon). When the fire-wood is ablaze- 02 They lift the (burning) fire-wood, and place it on the underlayer 2. Thereupon he says (to the Hotr̥), &amp;lsquo;Recite for Agni as he is taken forward 3!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/05/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/05/4/</guid>
      <description>01 It is for a twofold reason that the sounding-holes are dug. The cart-shed, truly, is the head of the sacrificer; and what four holes there are here in the head&amp;ndash;namely, these two and these two 1&amp;ndash;those he thereby makes: for this reason he digs the sounding-holes. 02 Now the gods and the Asuras, both of them sprung from Prajāpati, were contending. The Asuras then by way of witchcraft buried charms 2 within these worlds, thinking, &amp;lsquo;Peradventure we may thus overcome the gods.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
