<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०४ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/04/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०४ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/04/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>THE DASAPEYA.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/04/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/04/5/</guid>
      <description>01 Now when Varuṇa was consecrated, his lustre departed from him,&amp;ndash;lustre means vigour: that Vishṇu, the Sacrifice, it was he that departed from him,&amp;ndash;probably that collected essence of the waters wherewith he is anointed on that occasion, drove out his lustre. 02 He stole after it with those deities 1,&amp;ndash;with Savitr̥, the impeller (prasavitr̥); with Sarasvatī, speech; with Tvashṭr̥, the forms of being; with Pūshan, cattle; with Indra, on the part of him 2 (the Sacrificer); with Br̥haspati, holiness; with Varuṇa, might; with Agni, fiery spirit; with Soma, the King; &amp;ndash;but only through Vishṇu 3, the tenth deity, he found it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/04/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/04/1/</guid>
      <description>01 He puts a piece of copper 1 into the mouth of a long-haired man, with (Vāj. S. X, 10), &amp;lsquo;Removed by sacrifice are the mordacious.&amp;rsquo; For verily he who performs the Rājasūya escapes all kinds of death, all murderous blows, and old age alone is his death: hence whatever kind of death, whatever murderous blow there is, past that he now guides him, as past the mordacious ones. 02 And as to why it is of a long-haired man,&amp;ndash;such a long-haired man is neither woman nor man; for being a male, he is not a woman, and being longhaired (a eunuch), he is not a man.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/04/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/04/2/</guid>
      <description>01 He (the king) is anointed (sprinkled) whilst standing with his face turned towards the east. A Brāhman&amp;ndash;either the Adhvaryu, or he who is his (the king&amp;rsquo;s) court chaplain&amp;ndash;sprinkles him in front, from behind;&amp;ndash; 02 With (Vāj. S. X, 17), &amp;lsquo;With Soma&amp;rsquo;s glory I sprinkle thee,&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;with vigour&amp;rsquo; he thereby says; &amp;lsquo;With Agni&amp;rsquo;s glow . . . 1,&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;with vigour&amp;rsquo; he thereby says;&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;With Sūrya&amp;rsquo;s splendour . . .,&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;with vigour&amp;rsquo; he thereby says;&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;With Indra&amp;rsquo;s energy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/04/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/04/3/</guid>
      <description>01 North of the Āhavanīya he places a hundred, or more than a hundred, cows of that relative of his. The reason why he does so is this: 02 When Varuṇa was consecrated, his energy, his vigour departed from him. Probably 1 that collected essence (life-sap) of the waters wherewith they were sprinkling him, drove out his energy, his vigour. He found it in the cattle, and because he found it in them, therefore cattle are an object of respect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/04/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/04/4/</guid>
      <description>01 He proceeds with the curds for Mitra-Varuṇa. Whilst the Svishṭakr̥t of it remains yet unoffered, they bring a throne-seat for him (the king); for truly he who gains a seat in the air, gains a seat above (others): thus these subjects of his sit below him who is seated above,&amp;ndash;that is why they bring him a throne-seat. It is of khadira (acacia catechu) wood, and perforated, and bound with thongs as that of the Bhāratas.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
