<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०१ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/01/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०१ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/01/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>THE AGNISHTOMA. THE DÎKSHÂ,  CONSECRATION.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/01/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/01/1/</guid>
      <description>01 They choose a place of worship. Let them choose (the place) which lies highest, and above which no other part of the ground rises 1; for it was from thence that the gods ascended to heaven, and he who is consecrated indeed ascends to the gods. He thus sacrifices on a place of worship frequented by the gods; but were any other part of the ground to rise above it, he would indeed be lowered while sacrificing: let them therefore choose (the place) which lies highest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/01/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/01/2/</guid>
      <description>01 Let him perform the rite of consecration (dīkshā) 1 in the afternoon. Previously to the shaving of his hair and beard he may eat of what he likes, or whatever comes to hand; for hereafter his food consists of fast-milk (vrata) only. But, if he does not care to eat, he need not eat anything.
02 Thereupon they enclose a place 2 north of the hall, and place a vessel of water in it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/01/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/01/3/</guid>
      <description>01 Having brought water forward 1, he takes out (the material for) a cake on eleven potsherds for Agni and Vishṇu; for Agni is all the deities, since it is in Agni that offering is made to all the deities. Moreover Agni is the lower half, and Vishṇu is the upper half of the sacrifice: &amp;lsquo;I will become consecrated after encompassing all the deities, after encompassing the entire sacrifice,&amp;rsquo; thus he thinks, and hence there is a cake on eleven potsherds for Agni and Vishṇu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/01/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/01/4/</guid>
      <description>01 All formulas of the consecration are audgrabhaṇa (elevatory), since he who is consecrated elevates himself (ud-grabh) from this world to the world of the gods. He elevates himself by means of these same formulas, and therefore they say that all formulas of the consecration are &amp;lsquo;audgrabhaṇa.&amp;rsquo; Now they also (specially) designate these intermediate ones as &amp;lsquo;audgrabhaṇa,&amp;rsquo; because these are libations 1, and a libation is a sacrifice. For the muttering of a sacrificial formula is an occult (form of sacrifice), but a libation is a direct (form of) sacrifice: hence it is by this same sacrifice that he elevates himself from this world to the world of the gods.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
