<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०४ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/04/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०४ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/04/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>III. THE PINDAPITRIYAGÑA  OBLATION OF OBSEQUIAL CAKES TO THE FATHERS.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/04/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/04/2/</guid>
      <description>01 Now the living beings once approached Prajāpati&amp;ndash;beings doubtless mean creatures&amp;ndash;and said, &amp;lsquo;Ordain unto us in what manner we are to live!&amp;rsquo; Thereupon the gods, being properly invested with the sacrificial cord 1 and bending the right knee, approached him. To them he said, &amp;lsquo;The sacrifice (shall be) your food; immortality your sap; and the sun your light!&amp;rsquo; 02 Then the fathers approached, wearing the cord on the right shoulder, and bending the left knee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IV. THE ÂGRAYANESHTI  OFFERING OF FIRST-FRUITS.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/04/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/04/3/</guid>
      <description>01 Now Kahoḍa Kaushītaki spake, &amp;lsquo;This sap (of the plants) truly belongs to those two, heaven and earth: having offered of this sap to the gods, we will eat it.&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;That is why the offering of first-fruits is performed.&amp;rsquo; 02 And Yājñavalkya also spake:&amp;ndash;The gods and the Asuras, both of them sprung from Prajāpati, once contended for superiority. The Asuras then defiled, partly by magic, partly with poison, both kinds of plants&amp;ndash;those on which men and beasts subsist&amp;ndash;hoping that in this way they might over come the gods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE DÂKSHÂYANA SACRIFICE.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/04/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/04/4/</guid>
      <description>Here also two days were, as a rule, required for the performance, both at full and new moon; but while, at the ordinary sacrifice,
At full moon some authorities add a special ishṭi to Indra Vimr̥dh (&amp;rsquo;the Averter of evil&amp;rsquo;). The new-moon performance concludes with libations of whey to the divine coursers (the horses of the gods); and, optionally, with an ishṭi to Āditya.
The performance of the Dākshāyaṇa sacrifice was held to be obligatory only for a period of fifteen years (see XI, 1, 2, 13), whereas the ordinary new and full-moon offerings had to be performed for double that period from the setting up of the sacred fires.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/04/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/04/1/</guid>
      <description>01 Now after the performance of the Agnihotra he (optionally 1) .approaches the fires with (Vāj. S. III, 37), &amp;lsquo;Earth! ether! sky!&amp;rsquo; In saying &amp;lsquo;Earth! ether! sky!&amp;rsquo; he renders his speech auspicious by means of the truth, and with that (speech) thus rendered propitious he invokes a blessing:&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;May I be well supplied with offspring!&amp;rsquo; whereby he prays for offspring; &amp;lsquo;&amp;ndash;well supplied with men!&amp;rsquo; whereby he prays for men (heroes); &amp;lsquo;&amp;ndash;well supplied with viands!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
