<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०३ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/03/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०३ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/03/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/03/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/03/1/</guid>
      <description>01 Having drunk (Soma) 1 and said, &amp;lsquo;We are invited together 2,&amp;rsquo; he (the Adhvaryu) rises. He takes a piece of the cake, and at the place where the Acḥāvāka, being seated, is now (about to) recite, he puts the piece of cake in his hand and says, &amp;lsquo;O Acḥāvāka, say what thou hast to say!&amp;rsquo; Now, the Acḥāvāka was excluded (from the Soma) 3.
02 Indra and Agni preserved him for the production of creatures, whence the Acḥāvāka priest belongs to Indra and Agni.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/03/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/03/2/</guid>
      <description>01 Now truly when the Hotr̥ praises (recites the śastra 1), he sings, and to him thus singing the Adhvaryu responds (prati-ā-gar), whence the name response (pratigara).
02 [The Hotr̥] calls upon that (Adhvaryu) seated (before him) with his face towards the east 2. For all others except the Udgātr̥ perform their priestly duties while facing the east, and in this manner that priestly duty of his is performed towards the east.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/03/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/03/3/</guid>
      <description>01 He presses out (the Soma juice) with &amp;lsquo;Ihā̃! Ihā̃ 1!&amp;rsquo; (hither), whereby he draws Indra nigh; and with &amp;lsquo;Br̥hat! Br̥hat!&amp;rsquo; (great), whereby he draws Indra 2 nigh.
02 The Śukra and Manthin grahas he draws first, for thereby the Soma feast comes to be supplied with pure Soma (śukra). Thereupon the Āgrayaṇa, for that (cup) is drawn at all (three) feasts. Then the Marutvatīya cup; then the Ukthya, for here also there are songs of praise (Uktha) 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/03/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/03/4/</guid>
      <description>01 Now, they slay the sacrifice, when they spread (perform) it:&amp;ndash;to wit, when they press out the king (Soma), they slay him; when they quiet the victim, they slay it; and with mortar and pestle, with the upper and nether millstone, they slay the havis offering. 02 When slain, that sacrifice was no longer vigorous. By means of dakshiṇās (gifts to the priests) the gods invigorated it: hence the name dakshiṇā, because thereby they invigorated (dakshay) it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/03/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/03/5/</guid>
      <description>01 Now there are three kinds of gods,&amp;ndash;the Vasus, the Rudras, and the Ādityas. Between them the press-feasts are divided: the morning pressing belongs to the Vasus, the midday pressing to the Rudras, and the third pressing to the Ādityas. But the morning pressing belonged to the Vasus exclusively, and the midday pressing to the Rudras exclusively, and the third pressing to the Ādityas conjointly (with others). 02 The Ādityas then said, &amp;lsquo;As that morning pressing belongs exclusively to the Vasus, and that midday pressing exclusively to the Rudras, so offer ye now to us a libation before the common (pressing).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
