<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०२ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/02/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०२ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/02/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/02/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/02/1/</guid>
      <description>01 Prajāpati was desirous of going up to the world of heaven; but Prajāpati, indeed, is all the (sacrificial) animals 1&amp;ndash;man, horse, bull, ram, and he-goat:&amp;ndash;by means of these forms he could not do so. He saw this bird-like body, the fire-altar, and constructed it. He attempted to fly up, without contracting and expanding (the wings), but could not do so. By contracting and expanding (the wings) he did fly up: whence even to this day birds can only fly up when they contract their wings and spread their feathers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/02/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/02/2/</guid>
      <description>01 Now the one person which they made out of those seven persons 1 became this Prajāpati. He produced living beings (or offspring), and having produced living beings he went upwards,&amp;ndash;he went to that world where that (sun) now shines. And, indeed, there was then no other (victim) meet for sacrifice but that one (Prajāpati), and the gods set about offering him up in sacrifice. 02 Wherefore it is with reference to this that the R̥shi has said (Vāj.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/02/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/02/3/</guid>
      <description>01 Now this Vedi (altar-ground, viz. the Mahāvedi of the Soma-sacrifice) is just that (right) measure for the Vedi of the sevenfold 1 (fire-altar). Having fixed upon (the place for) the sacrificial ground, he enters the Patnīśāla 2 by the front (east) door, and having thrown up (the ground) for the Gārhapatya, he sprinkles it with water. From the raised (site) of the Gārhapatya he strides seven steps eastward. From there he measures off a fathom 3 towards the east, and having, in the middle thereof, thrown up (the ground) for the Āhavanīya, he sprinkles it with water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/02/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/02/4/</guid>
      <description>01 Prajāpati, indeed, is the year, and Agni is all objects of desire. This Prajāpati, the year, desired, &amp;lsquo;May I build up for myself a body so as to contain 1 Agni, all objects of desire.&amp;rsquo; He constructed a body one hundred and one-fold; and in constructing a body one hundred and one-fold, he built up for himself a body so as to contain Agni, all objects of desire, and himself became all objects of desire; there was not one object of desire outside of him: whence they say, &amp;lsquo;The year (includes) all objects of desire;&amp;rsquo; for, indeed, outside the year there is no object of desire whatever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/02/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/02/5/</guid>
      <description>01 Now as to the building itself. He builds between the two (performances of the) Upasads 1. For at that time the gods were afraid lest the fiends, the Rakshas, should destroy that (Agni&amp;rsquo;s body) of theirs (built) there 2. They saw these strongholds, the Upasads, to wit, these worlds, for these worlds are indeed strongholds. They entered them, and having entered them, they completed that body in a place free from danger and devilry; and in like manner does the Sacrificer now, after entering these strongholds, complete this body in a place free from danger and devilry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/02/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/02/6/</guid>
      <description>01 The one hundred and one-fold Prajāpati, doubtless, is the year, and thereto belong days and nights, half-months, months, and seasons. The days and nights of a month are sixty, and in the month, doubtless, the days and nights of the year are obtained; and there are twenty-four half-months, thirteen months, and three seasons (of four months)&amp;ndash;that makes a hundred parts, and the year itself is the one hundred and first part.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
