<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०४ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/04/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०४ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/04/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>THE ÂTITHYA,  GUEST-OFFERING (HOSPITABLE RECEPTION GIVEN TO KING SOMA).</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/04/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/04/1/</guid>
      <description>01 Verily, the guest-offering is the head of the sacrifice, and the Prāyaṇīya and Udayanīya are its arms. But the arms are on both sides of the head: therefore those two oblations, the Prāyaṇīya and Udayanīya, are on both sides of the guest-offering. 02 Now as to why it is called &amp;lsquo;guest-offering.&amp;rsquo; He, the purchased Soma, truly comes as his (the sacrificer&amp;rsquo;s) guest,&amp;ndash;to him (is offered) that (hospitable reception): even as for a king or a Brāhman one would cook a large ox or a large he-goat&amp;ndash;for that is human (fare offered to a guest), and the oblation is that of the gods&amp;ndash;so he prepares for him that guest-offering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE AVÂNTARADÎKSHÂ,  INTERMEDIARY CONSECRATION.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/04/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/04/3/</guid>
      <description>01 When the gods had performed the guest-offering, discord arose between them. They allayed it by means of the Tānūnaptra (oaths). They desired an atonement for having spoken evil to one another; for they had appointed no other consecration-ceremony till the expiatory bath. They perceived this intermediate consecration 1. 02 By means of fire they enveloped (the body) with a skin. Now, fire being fervour, and the consecration being fervour, they thereby underwent an intermediate consecration; and because they underwent that intermediate consecration, therefore this intermediary consecration (avāntaradīkshā, is performed).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE TÂNÛNAPTRA,  COVENANT OF TANÛNAPÂTxa0[^fn_247].</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/04/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/04/2/</guid>
      <description>01 When the gods had performed the guest-offering, discord befell them. They separated into four different parties, unwilling to yield to each other&amp;rsquo;s excellence,&amp;ndash;Agni, with the Vasus, Soma with the Rudras, Varuṇa with the Ādityas, and Indra with the Maruts. Br̥haspati with the All-gods, say some 1, but, indeed, those who separated into four parties were &amp;lsquo;all the gods.&amp;rsquo; When they were separated, the Asura-Rakshas came after them and entered between them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE UPASADS,  HOMAGES.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/04/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/04/4/</guid>
      <description>01 Verily the Upasads (homages or sieges) are the neck of the sacrifice, and the Pravargya is its head. Hence when it is performed with the Pravargya 1, they perform the Upasads 2 after performing the Pravargya, and thereby they put the neck in its place.
02 The anuvākyās (invitatory prayers) in the forenoon are the yājyās (offering prayers) in the afternoon; and the yājyās are the anuvākyās 3. He thus interlinks them, whence those joints and those bones of the neck are interlinked.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
