<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०४ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/04/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०४ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/04/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>THE MITRAVINDÂ SACRIFICE.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/04/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/04/3/</guid>
      <description>01 Prajāpati was becoming heated (by fervid devotion), whilst creating living beings 1. From him, worn out and heated, Śrī (Fortune and Beauty) came forth. She stood there resplendent, shining, and trembling 2. The gods, beholding her thus resplendent, shining, and trembling, set their minds upon her. 02 They said to Prajāpati, &amp;lsquo;Let us kill her and take (all) this from her.&amp;rsquo; He said, &amp;lsquo;Surely, that Śrī is a woman, and people do not kill a woman, but rather take (anything) from her (leaving her) alive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/04/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/04/1/</guid>
      <description>01 Now Uddālaka Āruṇi 1 was driving about 2, as a chosen (offering-priest), amongst the people of the northern country. By him a gold coin was offered; for in the time of our forefathers a prize used to be offered by chosen (priests) when driving about, for the sake of calling out the timid 3 to a disputation. Fear then seized the Brāhmaṇas of the northern people:&amp;ndash;
02 &amp;lsquo;This fellow is a Kurupañcāla Brahman, and son of a Brahman&amp;ndash;let us take care lest he should deprive us of our domain: come, let us challenge him to a disputation on spiritual matters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/04/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/04/2/</guid>
      <description>01 Now, then, as to the taking up of the two offering-spoons 1. Now, in this respect, some people, thinking themselves clever, take up the (guhū) with the right, and the upabhr̥t with the left (hand); but let him not do so; for if, in that case, any one were to say of him, &amp;lsquo;Surely, this Adhvaryu has made the Sacrificer&amp;rsquo;s spiteful enemy equal to him, and able to cope with him,&amp;rsquo; then that would indeed be likely to come to pass.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/04/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/11/04/4/</guid>
      <description>01 Now, as to the successful issue of the sacrificial food. Now, indeed, there are six doors to the Brahman 1&amp;ndash;to wit, fire, wind, the waters, the moon, lightning, and the sun. 02 He who offers with slightly burnt sacrificial food, enters through the fire-door 2 of the Brahman; and, by entering through the fire-door of the Brahman, he wins his union with, and participation in the world of, the Brahman.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
