<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०१ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/01/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०१ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/01/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/01/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/01/1/</guid>
      <description>01 The Upāṁśu (graha), forsooth, is the out-breathing of the Sacrifice 1, the Upāṁśu-savana (press-stone) the through-breathing, and the Antaryāma (graha) the in-breathing. 02 Now as to why it is called Upāṁśu. There is a graha called Aṁśu 2, that is Prajāpati: his out-breathing is this (graha); and because it is his out-breathing, therefore it is called Upāṁśu. 03 This (graha) he draws without a strainer 3: whereby he puts the out-breathing into him as one tending away from him, and thus this forward-tending out-breathing of his streams forth from him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/01/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/01/2/</guid>
      <description>01 The Upāṁśu (graha), forsooth, is his out-breathing, the Upāṁśu-savana (stone) his through-breathing, and the Antaryāma (graha) his in-breathing.
02 Now as to why it is called Antaryāma. That which is the out-breathing is also the in-breathing and the through-breathing. Now, in drawing the Upāṁśu (graha), he puts into him that out-breathing which tends away from him; and in drawing the Antaryāma, he puts into him that in-breathing which tends towards him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/01/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/01/3/</guid>
      <description>01 The Aindra-vāyava (graha), forsooth, is his speech; and as such belonging to his self 1. Now Indra, when he had hurled the thunderbolt at Vr̥tra, thinking himself to be the weaker, and fearing lest he had not laid him low, hid himself. The gods also hid themselves away in the same place. 02 The gods then said, &amp;lsquo;Verily, we know not if Vr̥tra be slain or alive: come, let one of us find out, if Vr̥tra be slain or alive!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/01/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/01/4/</guid>
      <description>01 Mitra and Varuṇa, forsooth, are his intelligence and will; and as such belonging to his self: whenever he desires anything in his mind, as &amp;lsquo;Would that this were mine! I might do this!&amp;rsquo; that is intelligence; and whenever that is accomplished, that is will 1. Now intelligence indeed is Mitra, and will is Varuṇa; and Mitra is the priesthood, and Varuṇa the nobility; and the priesthood is the conceiver, and the noble is the doer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/01/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/01/5/</guid>
      <description>01 The Āśvina graha 1, forsooth, is his organ of hearing; hence in drinking it he turns (the cup) all round 2, since with that ear of his he hears all round.&amp;ndash;Now when the Bhr̥gus, or the Aṅgiras, attained the heavenly world, Cyavana the Bhārgava, or Cyavana the Āṅgirasa, was left behind here (on earth) decrepit and ghostlike 3. 02 But Śaryāta, the Mānava, just then wandered about here with his tribe, and settled near by that same place.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
