<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०८ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/08/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०८ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/08/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/08/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/08/1/</guid>
      <description>01 Now, when Indra&amp;rsquo;s energies, or vital powers, departed from him, the gods restored them by means of this very sacrifice. Both cups of milk and cups of Surā-liquor are filled: they thereby restore to him his energies, or vital powers. On the northern fire they offer (from) the cups of milk, and thereby provide him 1 with the bright liquor, with the Soma-drink. 02 He (the Adhvaryu) offers (of the three cups of milk) with (Vāj.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/08/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/08/2/</guid>
      <description>01 Prajāpati created the (Soma-)sacrifice. He took it and performed it. When he had performed it, he felt like one emptied out. He saw this sacrificial performance, the Sautrāmaṇī, and performed it, and then he was again replenished; and, indeed, he who performs the Soma-sacrifice is, as it were, emptied out, for his wealth, his prosperity is, as it were, taken from him. 02 Having performed a Soma-sacrifice one ought to perform the Sautrāmaṇī: as a cow that has been milked would replenish again, even so, indeed, does he replenish himself,&amp;ndash;he replenishes himself by offspring and cattle; and, verily, he who, knowing this, performs the Sautrāmaṇī, or he who (even) knows this, establishes himself in this world, and wins the heavenly world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/08/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/08/3/</guid>
      <description>01 Tvashṭr̥, seeing his son slain, brought Soma suitable for witchery, and withheld from Indra. Indra, committing a desecration of the sacrifice, by main force drank off his (Tvashṭr̥&amp;rsquo;s) Soma juice. He went asunder in every direction,&amp;ndash;from his mouth and vital airs his excellence and fame passed away, and entered the cattle, whence cattle are one&amp;rsquo;s fame: and famous, indeed, is he who, knowing this, is consecrated 1 by the Sautrāmaṇī.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
