<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०२ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/02/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०२ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/02/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>II. THE AGNIHOTRA  MORNING AND EVENING LIBATIONS;  THE AGNY-UPASTHÂNA  HOMAGE TO THE FIRES.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/02/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/02/4/</guid>
      <description>01 Prajāpati alone, indeed, existed here in the beginning. He considered, &amp;lsquo;How may I be reproduced?&amp;rsquo; He toiled and performed acts of penance. He generated Agni from his mouth; and because he generated him from his mouth, therefore Agni is a consumer of food: and, verily, he who thus knows Agni to be a consumer of food, becomes himself a consumer of food.
02 He thus generated him first (agre) of the gods; and therefore (he is called) Agni, for agni (they say) is the same as agri.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE OBLATIONS.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/02/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/02/1/</guid>
      <description>01 When he has taken out the Āhavanīya fire 1, he performs the Full-offering 2. The reason why he performs the full-offering is that he thereby causes that Agni to become an eater of food for his own self; that he thereby offers food to him. Even as (a mother or cow) would offer the breast to a new-born child or calf, so does he thereby offer food to him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE PUNARÂDHEYA OR RE-ESTABLISHMENT OF THE SACRED FIRESxa0[^fn_707].</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/02/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/02/3/</guid>
      <description>01 Now Varuṇa established this (fire), being desirous of sovereignty. He obtained sovereignty; and, accordingly, whether one (who has established the fires) knows (this) or not, they call him &amp;lsquo;king Varuṇa.&amp;rsquo; Soma (established the fire), being desirous of glory. He became glorious, and, accordingly, whether one obtains a hold on Soma, or whether one does not, they both obtain (glory),&amp;ndash;for it is glory that people thereby get to see. Glorious therefore he becomes, and sovereignty he obtains, whosoever, knowing this, establishes a sacrificial fire of his own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/02/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/02/2/</guid>
      <description>01 Now, in performing that sacrifice, they slay it; and in pressing out the king (Soma), they slay him; and in quieting and immolating the victim, they slay it. The haviryajña they slay with the mortar and pestle, and with the two mill-stones. 02 When slain, that sacrifice was no longer vigorous. By means of dakshiṇās (gifts to the priests) the gods again invigorated it: hence the name dakshiṇā, because thereby they invigorated (dakshay) that (sacrifice).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
