<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०३ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/03/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०३ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/03/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/03/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/03/1/</guid>
      <description>01 &amp;lsquo;Seeing that all this threefold universe keeps passing into one another, O Bālāki, how is it that these,&amp;ndash;to wit, the sacrifice, Man, and Prajāpati,&amp;ndash;do not exceed one another?
02 Seeing that the upward Stomas follow the sacrifice, fitting themselves by repetitions with Sāmans, how do they enter man, and how do they become united with the vital airs? 03 The Prāyaṇīya Atirātra, the Caturviṁśa day, the four Abhiplavas, and the Pr̥shṭḥya (shaḍaha):how do these enter man, and how do they become united with the vital airs?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/03/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/03/2/</guid>
      <description>01 The Year is Man 1:&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;Man&amp;rsquo; is one unit, and &amp;lsquo;year&amp;rsquo; is another, and these now are one and the same;&amp;ndash;there are in the year the two, day and night, and in man there are these two breathings, and these now are one and the same;&amp;ndash;there are three seasons in the year, and these three breathings in man, and these (two) now are one and the same;&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;saṁvatsara (year)&amp;rsquo; consists of four syllables, and so does &amp;lsquo;yajamāna (sacrificer),&amp;rsquo; and these (two) now are one and the same;&amp;ndash;there are five seasons in the year, and these five breathings in man, and these (two) now are one and the same;&amp;ndash;there are six seasons in the year, and these six breathings in man, and these (two) now are one and the same;&amp;ndash;there are seven seasons in the year, and these seven breathings in man, and these (two) now are one and the same.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/03/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/03/3/</guid>
      <description>01 The gods were once performing the initiation ceremony for a (sacrificial session) of a thousand years. When five hundred years had passed with them, everything here was worn out&amp;ndash;to wit, Stomas, and Pr̥shṭḥas, and metres (texts). 02 The gods then perceived that unexhausted element of the sacrifice, and by means of that unexhausted element they obtained what success there was in the Veda; and, verily, for him who thus knows this, the Vedas are unexhausted, and the work of the officiating priests is pet-formed with the unexhausted threefold science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/03/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/03/4/</guid>
      <description>01 Prajāpati once upon a time spake unto Purusha Nārāyaṇa, &amp;lsquo;Offer sacrifice! offer sacrifice!&amp;rsquo; He spake, &amp;lsquo;Verily, thou sayest to me, &amp;ldquo;Offer sacrifice! offer sacrifice!&amp;rdquo; and thrice have I offered sacrifice: by the morning-service the Vasus went forth, by the midday-service the Rudras, and by the evening-service the Ādityas; now I have but the offering-place 1, and on the offering-place I am sitting.&amp;rsquo;
02 He spake, &amp;lsquo;Offer yet sacrifice! I will tell thee such a thing that thy hymns shall be strung as a pearl on a thread, or a thread through a pearl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/03/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/03/5/</guid>
      <description>01 Of old, indeed, they were wont to seize this victim as one dedicated to Savitr̥, but now they seize it as one dedicated to Prajāpati, saying, &amp;lsquo;Savitr̥, in truth, is the same as Prajāpati.&amp;rsquo; It is therefore after having thrown together the (sacrificial) fires that they ought to perform this (animal) sacrifice on the Gr̥hapati&amp;rsquo;s own fires, thinking, &amp;lsquo;May we also have a share in this tail (of the. victim) wherewith they are now making offering together to the wives (of the gods).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
