<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०५ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/05/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०५ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/05/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>THE DVÂDASÂHAxa0[^fn_935].</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/05/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/05/4/</guid>
      <description>01 Now, at first the gods were all alike, all good. Of them, being all alike, all good, three desired, &amp;lsquo;May we be superior 1!&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;Agni, Indra, and Sūrya. 02 They went on praising and toiling. They saw those Atigrāhyas 3, and drew (grah) them for themselves over and above (ati): hence the name Atigrāhyas. They became superior, even as they are now superior 4 and verily he becomes superior for whomsoever, knowing this, they draw those cups of Soma.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/05/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/05/1/</guid>
      <description>01 He proceeds with the rice-pap to Aditi, as the concluding oblation. The reason why there is a rice-pap for Aditi is this. Because, on that former occasion 1, the gods said to her, &amp;lsquo;Thine forsooth shall be the opening, and thine the concluding oblation,&amp;rsquo; therefore he prepares that share for her at both ends (of the Soma-sacrifice). 02 And because, on that occasion, he offers when about to go forth (upa-pra-i) to buy the king (Soma), therefore that (opening oblation) is called Prāyaṇīya.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/05/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/05/10/</guid>
      <description>01 If the Soma is carried off, let him say, &amp;lsquo;Run about and seek!&amp;rsquo; If they find it, why should they care? But if they do not find it, atonement is made therefore. 02 Now there are two kinds of Phālguna plants, the red-flowering and the brown-flowering. Those Phālguna plants which have brown flowers one may press; for they, the brown-flowering Phālgunas, are akin to the Soma-plant: therefore he may press those with brown flowers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/05/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/05/2/</guid>
      <description>01 They lay hands on the barren cow 1, and having laid hands on it, they quiet it. It having been quieted 2, he says (to the slaughterer), &amp;lsquo;Pull out the omentum!&amp;rsquo; The omentum having been pulled out 2, let him tell (the slaughterer) to search groping for an embryo. If they do not find one, why need they care? and if they find one, atonement is made therefore. 02 For surely it is not right that, thinking it to be one (cow), they should perform, as it were, with that one; or that, thinking them to be two, they should perform, as it were, with two 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/05/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/05/3/</guid>
      <description>01 The Shodaśin 1 (graha) forsooth is Indra. Now, at one time the beings surpassed (ati-ric) Indra&amp;ndash;the beings being the creatures&amp;ndash;they were in a state of equality, as it were, with him.
02 Indra then bethought himself, &amp;lsquo;How can I stand forth over everything here, and how may everything here be beneath me?&amp;rsquo; He saw that graha, and drew it for himself. Then he stood forth over everything here, and everything here was beneath him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/05/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/05/5/</guid>
      <description>01 Prajāpati, forsooth, is that sacrifice which is performed here, and from which these creatures have been produced: and in like manner are they produced thereafter even to this day. 02 After the Upāṁśu cup goats are produced. Now that (cup) is again employed in the sacrifice: hence creatures are here produced again and again. 03 After the Antāryama cup sheep are produced. Now that (cup) is again employed at the sacrifice: hence creatures are here produced again and again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/05/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/05/6/</guid>
      <description>01 Prajāpati, forsooth, is that sacrifice which is here performed, and whence these creatures have been produced, and in like manner are they produced therefrom even to this day. Having drawn the Aśvina graha, he makes (the sacrificer) eye (the several cups, while muttering) the Avakāśa formulas 1. 02 The Upāṁśu cup he eyes first with (Vāj. S. VII, 27), &amp;lsquo;For mine out-breathing, (a) giver of lustre 2, become thou pure for lustre!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/05/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/05/7/</guid>
      <description>01 Now, there are here thirty-four utterances, called expiations 1. Prajāpati, forsooth, is that sacrifice which is performed here, and from which these creatures have been produced,&amp;ndash;and in like manner are they produced therefrom even to this day. 02 There are eight Vasus, eleven Rudras, twelve Ādityas; and these two, Heaven and Earth, are the (thirty-second and) thirty-third. And there are thirty-three gods, and Prajāpati is the thirty-fourth;&amp;ndash;thus he makes him (the sacrificer, or Yajña) to be Prajāpati 2: now that 3 is, for that is immortal, and what is immortal that is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/05/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/05/8/</guid>
      <description>01 Now when at that Trirātra 1 sacrifice he gives those thousand (cows), then that one is made the one-thousandth 2. On the first day he brings three hundred and thirty-three; and likewise on the second day he brings three hundred and thirty-three; and likewise on the third day he brings three hundred and thirty-three. Then that one-thousandth is left over. 02 She should be three-coloured, they say, for that is the most perfect form for her.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/05/9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/05/9/</guid>
      <description>01 When he performs a twelve days’ sacrifice with transposed metres (Dvādaśāha vyūḍḥacḥandas), then he (the Adhvaryu) transposes the grahas (cups of Soma); and both the Udgātr̥ and the Hotr̥ transpose the metres. Now there is first that normal Tryaha (triduum), with settled metres 1: there he draws the cup beginning with the Aindravāyava. 02 Then, on the fourth day, he transposes the grahas, and they transpose the metres. There he draws the cups beginning with the Āgrayaṇa,&amp;ndash;for that fourth day is Prajāpati&amp;rsquo;s own; and the Āgrayaṇa is the self, and Prajāpati is the self: therefore he draws the cups beginning with the Āgrayaṇa.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
