<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०३ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/03/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०३ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/03/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>THE THIRD LAYER.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/03/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/03/1/</guid>
      <description>01 He lays down the third layer. For the gods, having laid down the second layer, now ascended it; but, indeed, they thereby completed and ascended to what is above the earth and below the atmosphere. 02 They spate, &amp;lsquo;Meditate ye!&amp;rsquo; whereby, indeed, they meant to say, &amp;lsquo;Seek ye a layer! Seek ye (to build) upwards from hence!&amp;rsquo; Whilst meditating, they saw the great third layer, even the air: that world pleased them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/03/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/03/2/</guid>
      <description>01 He then lays down a Viśvajyotis (all-light brick). Now the middle Viśvajyotis is Vāyu 1, for Vāyu (the wind) is all the light in the air-world: it is Vāyu he thus places therein. He places it so as not to be separated from the regional (bricks): he thus places Vāyu in the regions, and hence there is wind in all the regions. 02 And, again, as to why he lays down the Viśvajyotis,&amp;ndash;the Viśvajyotis, doubtless, is offspring (or creatures), for offspring indeed is all the light: he thus lays generative power (into that world).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/03/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/03/3/</guid>
      <description>01 He then lays down the Cḥandasyā 1 (metres’ bricks). Now the metres are cattle, and the middle-most layer is the air: he thus places cattle in the air, whence cattle have their abode in the air. 02 And, again, as to why he lays down Cḥandasyās,&amp;ndash;the metres are cattle, and cattle are food, and the middlemost layer is the middle (of Agni, the altar): he thus places food in the middle (of Agni&amp;rsquo;s body).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/03/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/08/03/4/</guid>
      <description>01 He then lays down the Vālakhilyās;&amp;ndash;the Vālakhilyās, doubtless, are the vital airs: it is the vital airs he thus lays (into Agni). And as to why they are called Vālakhilyās,&amp;ndash;what (unploughed piece of ground lies) between two cultivated fields is called &amp;lsquo;khila;&amp;rsquo; and these (channels of the) vital airs 1 are separated from each other by the width of a horsehair (vāla), and because they are separated from each other by the width of a horse-hair, they (the bricks) are called Vālakhilyās.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
