<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०३ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/09/03/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०३ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/09/03/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>INSTALLATION AND CONSECRATION OF AGNI.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/09/03/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/09/03/1/</guid>
      <description>01 He then offers the Vaiśvānara (cake). That Agni has now been completely restored; he now is that deity, (Agni) Vaiśvānara (belonging to all men): to him he offers this oblation, and by the oblation he makes him a deity, for whatever deity an oblation is prepared that is a deity, but not one for whom no (oblation) is prepared. It is one of twelve potsherds: twelve months are a year, and Vaiśvānara is the year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/09/03/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/09/03/2/</guid>
      <description>01 Thereupon 1 he (the Sacrificer 2) offers the Vasor dhārā. That whole Agni has now been completed, and he is here the Vasu (good one): to that Vasu the gods offered this shower (dhārā), whence it is called &amp;lsquo;Vasor dhārā 3;&amp;rsquo; and in like manner this (Sacrificer) offers to him this shower, and gratifies him thereby. 02 And, again, as to why he offers the &amp;lsquo;Vasor dhārā;&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;this is his (Agni&amp;rsquo;s) Abhisheka 4; for the gods, having now completed him wholly and entirely, showered upon him those wishes (or, objects of desire), this &amp;lsquo;Vasor dhārā;&amp;rsquo; and in like manner does this (Sacrificer), now that he has completed him wholly and entirely, shower upon him those wishes, this &amp;lsquo;Vasor dhārā.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/09/03/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/09/03/3/</guid>
      <description>01 He then offers these Yajñakratus 1 (sacrificial rites), with,&amp;rsquo; May the Agni and the Gharma (prosper) for me!&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;by these sacrificial rites he thus gratifies him, and by these sacrificial rites he thus consecrates him. 02 He then offers (the libations relating to) the Uneven Stomas 2;&amp;ndash;for the gods, having now obtained their desires, by means of the uneven Stomas went up to heaven; and in like manner does the Sacrificer, now that he has obtained all his desires, by means of the uneven Stomas go up to heaven.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/09/03/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/09/03/4/</guid>
      <description>01 He then offers the Vājaprasavīya 1 (set of fourteen libations),&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;vāja&amp;rsquo; (strength, sustenance) means food (anna): it thus is an &amp;lsquo;anna-prasavīya&amp;rsquo; for him, and it is food he thereby raises (pra-sū) for him (Agni). 02 For the gods, now that they had gratified him by that food, and consecrated him by those objects of desire, (to wit) by that stream of wealth 2, hereby gratified him once more; and in like manner does this (Sacrificer), now that he has gratified him by that food, and consecrated him by those objects of desire, that shower of wealth, hereby gratify him once more.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
