<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०९ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/09/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०९ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/09/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/09/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/09/1/</guid>
      <description>01 Verily, from this sacrifice the man 1 is born and whatever food a man consumes in this world, that (food), in return, consumes him in yonder world. Now this sacrifice is performed by means of spirituous liquor, and spirituous liquor (parisrut) is not to be consumed by a Brāhmaṇa: he thus is born from that which is not (to be) consumed, and the food does not, in return, consume him in yonder world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/09/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/09/3/</guid>
      <description>01 Now, Dushṭarītu Pauṁsāyana had been expelled from the kingdom which had come down to him through ten generations; and the Sr̥ñjayas also expelled Revottaras Pāṭava Kākra Sthapati. 02 He said to Dushṭarītu Pauṁsāyana, &amp;lsquo;I will perform the Sautrāmaṇī for thee, and will comer upon thee that dominion over the Sr̥ñjayas.&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;So be it!&amp;rsquo; he replied. So he performed it for him. 03 Now Balhika Prātipīya, the Kauravya king, heard (people say) this&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;There is that Dushṭarītu Pauṁsāyana who has been expelled from the kingdom which has come down to him through ten generations: for him that Cākra Sthapati wants to perform the Sautrāmaṇī and to confer upon him the dominion over the Sr̥ñjayas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/09/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/09/4/</guid>
      <description>01 Having performed the sacrifice they betake themselves to the purificatory bath; for after a Soma-sacrifice they do betake themselves to the purificatory bath, and the Sautrāmaṇī is the same as the Soma (sacrifice). 02 [He plunges the mash-pot into the water, with Vāj. S. XX, 14-18 1,] &amp;lsquo;Whatever contumely against the gods, O divine gods, we have committed, from that sin may Agni deliver me; may he deliver me from all trouble!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
