<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०३ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/03/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०३ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/03/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>THE KINDLING OF THE FIRE, THE PRAVARA, AND THE TWO LIBATIONS (ÂGHÂRA) OF BUTTER.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/03/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/03/5/</guid>
      <description>01 With the fire-wood (idhma, lighting material) the Adhvaryu lights (indh) the fire: hence it is called fire-wood. And with the kindling verses (sāmidhenī) the Hotr̥ kindles (sam-indh, to make blaze): hence they are called kindling verses. 02 He (the Adhvaryu 1) says (to the Hotr̥): &amp;lsquo;Recite to the fire as it is being kindled!&amp;rsquo; for it is to the fire, when it is being kindled, that he recites. 03 Here now some people say, &amp;lsquo;O Hotar, recite to the fire as it is being kindled!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/03/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/03/1/</guid>
      <description>01 He (the Āgnīdhra) now brushes the spoons 1 (with the grass-ends). The reason why he brushes the spoons is that the course 2 pursued among the gods is in accordance with that pursued among men. Now, when the serving up of food is at hand among men,&amp;ndash;
02 They rinse the vessels, and having rinsed them, they serve up the food with them: in the same way is treated the sacrifice to the gods, that is to say, the cooked oblations and the prepared altar; and those vessels of theirs, the sacrificial spoons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/03/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/03/2/</guid>
      <description>01 Now the sacrifice is the man. The sacrifice is the man for the reason that the man spreads (performs) it; and that in being spread it is made of exactly the same extent as the man 1: this is the reason why the sacrifice is the man. 02 The juhū (spoon) further belongs to that (man-shaped sacrifice), and so does the upabhr̥t; and the dhruvā 2 represents its trunk. Now it is from the trunk that all these limbs proceed, and for this reason the entire sacrifice proceeds from the dhruvā.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/03/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/03/3/</guid>
      <description>01 The Adhvaryu takes the sprinkling-water, and sprinkles in the first place the fire-wood 1, with the text (Vāj. S. II, 1), &amp;lsquo;A black deer, living in the den, art thou 2; I sprinkle thee, agreeable to Agni!&amp;rsquo; He thereby makes it sacrificially pure for Agni.
02 He then sprinkles he altar, with the text (Vāj. S. II, 1), &amp;lsquo;Thou art the altar; I sprinkle thee, agreeable to the barhis (sacrificial-grass covering)!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/03/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/03/4/</guid>
      <description>01 They should be green (fresh); for that is (what constitutes) their living element, by that they are vigorous, by that possessed of strength: for this reason they should be green. 02 The middle stick he lays down first (on the west side of the fire), with the text (Vāj. S. II, 3), &amp;lsquo;May the Gandharva Viśvāvasu 1 lay thee around for the security of the All! Thou art a fence to the sacrificer, thou (art) Agni, invoked and worthy of invocation!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
