<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०६ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/06/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०६ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/06/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>THE GAVÂM AYANAxa0[^fn_988].</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/06/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/06/2/</guid>
      <description>01 Verily, they who sit (sacrificing) for a year, by means of six months go to him that burns yonder: so it is told on the part of the Sāman, in as much as it is made of the form of that (sun) it is told on the part of the R̥k 1; and now in like manner on the part of the Yajus, by means of preparatory rite, when they draw that (graha) 2, they thereby also go to him (the sun).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/06/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/06/1/</guid>
      <description>01 Now, the Aṁśu (graha), forsooth, is no other than Prajāpati: that (cup) is his (Yajña&amp;rsquo;s or the Sacrificer&amp;rsquo;s) self 1, for Prajāpati is the self. Hence when they draw that (cup) they produce that self of his. Therein they lay these vital airs, according to as these vital airs, the grahas, are explained 2; and verily the sacrificer is born with his whole body in yonder world.
02 Where they draw that (cup), then that is (like) having a hold 3; and where they do not draw it, then that is (like) having no hold: therefore, then, he draws the Aṁśu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/06/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/06/3/</guid>
      <description>01 Now as to the manner of animal offerings. One may perform with the (ordinary) set of eleven victims. He seizes one for Agni as the first victim, and one for Varuṇa (as the last); then again one for Agni.: in this way let him perform with the set of eleven victims 1. 02 Or one may day after day seize a victim for Indra and Agni; for all the gods are Agni, since in Agni offering is made to all the deities; and Indra is the deity of the sacrifice: thus he neither offends any of the deities, nor does he offend him who is the deity of the sacrifice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/06/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/06/4/</guid>
      <description>01 Then as to the Mahāvratīya (graha) 1. Now when Prajāpati had created the living beings, his joints were relaxed: with his relaxed joints he was unable to raise himself. Then the gods went on praising and toiling. They saw this Mahāvratīya (cup) and drew it for him: thereby they restored his joints.
02 With his joints thus restored, he approached this food, what food of Prajāpati there is,&amp;ndash;for what eating is to men, that the vrata (fast-food, or religious observance generally) is to the gods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/06/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/06/5/</guid>
      <description>01 Now the graha 1, forsooth, is he that burns yonder, since by him all these creatures are held (swayed). Hence they say, &amp;lsquo;We take (grab) the grahas,&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;They walk, seized by the grahas.&amp;rsquo; 02 The graha, forsooth, is Vāc (speech); for by speech everything is swayed (grab) here 2,&amp;ndash;what wonder, then 3, that Vāc is the graha? 03 The graha, forsooth, is the name, for everything is held (fixed) by a name here,&amp;ndash;what wonder, then, that the name is the graha?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/06/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/06/6/</guid>
      <description>01 Now once on a time the gods, while performing sacrifice, were afraid of an attack from the Asura-Rakshas. They said, &amp;lsquo;Who of us shall sit on the south side; we will then enter upon the sacrifice on the north side in a place free from danger and injury.&amp;rsquo; 02 They said, &amp;lsquo;He who is the strongest of us, let him sit on the south side; we will then enter upon the sacrifice on the north side in a place free from danger and injury.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/06/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/06/7/</guid>
      <description>01 Threefold, forsooth, is science; the R̥cs, the Yajus, and the Sāmans. The R̥cs are this (earth), since it is thereon that he who sings them, does sing them; the R̥cs are speech, since it is by speech that he who sings them, does sing them. And the Yajus, forsooth, are the air, and the Sāmans the sky. That same threefold science is used in the Soma-sacrifice. 02 By the R̥c he conquers this world, by the Yajus the air, and by the Sāman the sky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/06/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/06/8/</guid>
      <description>01 Now the consecration-ceremony 1 (for the sacrificial session) is a sitting down, is a session (sattra): hence they say of them, &amp;rsquo;they sit.&amp;rsquo; And when thereafter they perform the sacrifice, then they (under)go; then he, who is the leader, leads: hence they say of them, &amp;rsquo;they (under)go 2.&#39; 02 The consecration-ceremony, then, is a sitting down, it is a session, it is an (under)going, it is the (under)going of a session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/06/9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/06/9/</guid>
      <description>01 Now, once on a time, the gods were sitting 1 in a sacrificial session, thinking, &amp;lsquo;May we attain excellence; may we be glorious, may we be eaters of food!&amp;rsquo; That same food, gained by them, wished to go away from them,&amp;ndash;and, food being cattle, it was the cattle that wished to go away from them, thinking, &amp;lsquo;It is to be feared lest they, being exhausted, may hurt us 2: how, indeed, will they deal with us?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
