<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०९ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/09/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०९ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/09/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>THE PATNÎSAMYÂGAS. CONCLUDING CEREMONIES.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/09/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/09/2/</guid>
      <description>01 Being about to perform the patnīsaṁyājas 1, they betake themselves back to the Gārhapatya fire. The Adhvaryu takes the juhū and sruva, the Hotr̥ the veda, and the Āgnīdhra the butter-(melting) pot. 02 Here now the Adhvaryu, according to some, passes the Āhavanīya on the east side. Let him not, however, do this; for were he to walk on that side, he would be outside the sacrifice. 03 According to others, the Adhvaryu walks (so as to pass) behind the (sacrificer&amp;rsquo;s) wife 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/09/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/09/1/</guid>
      <description>01 Now 1 when (the Adhvaryu) says, &amp;lsquo;The divine Hotr̥s are summoned for the proclamation of success, the human one is called upon for the song of praise (sūkta-vāka);&amp;rsquo; and when the Hotr̥ thereupon recites, he recites good words only 2: he thereby invokes a blessing on the sacrificer. It is indeed after the sacrifice that he thus invokes a blessing. A twofold reason there is for his invoking the blessing after the sacrifice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/09/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/09/3/</guid>
      <description>01 The sacrifice being now complete, he (the Adhvaryu) walks round (the fire) to the south, and pours out a vessel (of water); for thus it is (poured out) towards north: therefore he pours it out after walking round to the south, He who sacrifices, doubtless, sacrifices with a desire that he also may obtain a place in the world of the gods. That sacrifice of his then goes forth towards the world of the gods: after it follows the fee which he gives (to the priests), and holding on to the priests&amp;rsquo; fee (follows) the sacrificer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
