<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०७ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/06/07/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०७ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/06/07/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/06/07/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/06/07/1/</guid>
      <description>01 He hangs a gold plate (round his neck), and wears it; for that gold plate is the truth, and the truth is able to sustain that (fire 1): by means of the truth the gods carried it, and by means of the truth does he now carry it. 02 Now that truth is the same as yonder sun. It is a gold (plate), for gold is light, and he (the sun) is the light; gold is immortality, and he is immortality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/06/07/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/06/07/2/</guid>
      <description>01 Standing he puts on that (gold plate) 1,&amp;ndash;for that gold plate is yonder sun, and yonder sun stands, as it were; and moreover, while standing one is stronger. [He does so] standing with his face towards north-east: the significance of this has been explained. 02 [Vāj. S. XII, 1; R̥k S. X, 45, 8] &amp;lsquo;Looking like 2 a golden disk he hath shone far and wide,&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;for that gold plate, being seen, indeed shines far and wide;&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;flashing forth unquenchable 3 life for glory,&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;for not easily dying is his (Agni&amp;rsquo;s) life (vital power); and for glory he does shine;&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;Agni became immortal by his powers, when Dyaus bore him&amp;ndash;,&amp;rsquo; for Dyaus (the sky) did bear him;&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;she that hath good seed&amp;ndash;,&amp;rsquo; for good seed indeed she has whose seed he (Agni) is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/06/07/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/06/07/3/</guid>
      <description>01 He then holds it (the fire in the pan) up thus (towards north-east). Now the gods at that time were desiring, &amp;lsquo;May we be like Parjanya (the rain-god)!&amp;rsquo; By that body (of his 1) they became like Parjanya, and in like manner does the Sacrificer by that body (of his) become like Parjanya. 02 [Vāj. S. XII, 6; R̥k S. X, 45, 4] &amp;lsquo;Agni roared like the thundering sky,&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;for he (Agni) indeed roars like the thundering Parjanya;&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;again and again licking the ground, stroking 2 the plants,&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;for Parjanya, whilst licking again and again the ground, does stroke the plants;&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;scarce born, the kindled shone forth,&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;for scarce born he indeed lights up everything here;&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;with his light he shineth between the two worlds,&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;the two worlds, doubtless, are the heaven and the earth, and these two he indeed illumes by his light.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/06/07/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/06/07/4/</guid>
      <description>01 He then stands by him worshipping with the Vātsapra rite 1, For Prajāpati, having by means of the Vishṇu-strides produced creatures, created vital power for them by means of the Vātsapra rite; and in like manner the Sacrificer, having, by means of the Vishṇu-strides, produced creatures (or, subjects), creates vital power for them by means of the Vātsapra rite. 02 Now the Vātsapra rite, doubtless, is he, the golden-handed 2 (Agni);&amp;ndash;hence whomsoever that is born one may wish to obtain the full (measure of) life, let him touch that one with the Vātsapra rite, and he thereby creates vital power for that newborn one; and accordingly that one obtains the full (measure of) life.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
