<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०१ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/01/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०१ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/01/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>THE ASVAMEDHA, OR HORSE-SACRIFICE. PRELIMINARY CEREMONIESxa0[^fn_676].</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/01/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/01/1/</guid>
      <description>01 He (the Adhvaryu) cooks the priests’ mess of rice 1: it is seed he thereby produces. Having greased a rope with the ghee which is left over 2, he takes it; for ghee is (a type of) fiery spirit, and the horse is sacred to Prajāpati 3: he thus endows Prajāpati with fiery spirit. Impure, and unfit for sacrifice, indeed, is that (animal), to wit, the horse. 02 The rope consists of darbha grass (poa cynosuroides);&amp;ndash;for darbha stalks 4 are a means of purification: he thus purifies that (horse), and immolates it as one purified and meet for sacrifice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE INITIATION OF THE SACRIFICER.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/01/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/01/7/</guid>
      <description>01 Prajāpati desired, &amp;lsquo;Might I perform a horse-sacrifice 1?&amp;rsquo; He toiled and practised fervid devotion. From the body of him, when wearied and heated, the deities departed in a sevenfold way: therefrom the Dīkshā (initiation) was produced. He perceived those Vaiśvadeva 2 (oblations). He offered them, and by means of them he gained the Dīkshā: and when the Sacrificer offers the Vaiśvadeva (oblations) it is the Dīkshā he thereby gains. Day after day he offers them: day after day he thus gains the Dīkshā 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/01/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/01/2/</guid>
      <description>01 Now, unsuccessful in the sacrifice, assuredly, is what is performed without a formula. (With Vāj. S. XXII, 2,) &amp;lsquo;This rope did they take, at the first age of the truth, [the sages, at the rites: it hath been with us at this Soma-sacrifice, declaring the course in the gaining of the truth],&amp;rsquo; he takes the halter of the horse in order to supply a formula for the success of the sacrifice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/01/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/01/3/</guid>
      <description>01 Even as some of the havis (offering-material) may be spilled before it is offered, so also (part) of the victim is here spilled in that they let loose the sprinkled (horse) before it is slain. When he offers the Stokīyās (oblations of drops), he offers that (horse) as a complete offering 1&amp;ndash;so as to make good any spilling 2; for unspilled is any (part) of the offered (material) that is spilled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/01/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/01/4/</guid>
      <description>01 Prajāpati poured forth the life-sap of the horse (aśva-medha) 1. When poured forth, it went straight away from him and spread itself over the regions. The gods went in quest of it. By means of offerings (ishṭi) they followed it up, by offerings they searched for it, and by offerings they found it. And when he performs ishṭis, the Sacrificer thereby searches for the horse (aśva) meet for sacrifice 2 (medhya).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/01/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/01/5/</guid>
      <description>01 But, indeed, distinction, royal sway, departs from him who performs the horse-sacrifice; and when a man attains to distinction, the lute is played to him. Two Brāhmaṇical lute-players sing (and play) for a year; for that&amp;ndash;to wit, the lute&amp;ndash;is a form (attribute) of distinction: it is distinction they thus confer upon him. 02 Concerning this they say, ‘Were both to be Brāhmaṇas who sing, noble rank (or political power) would depart from him; for he&amp;ndash;to wit, a Brāhmaṇa&amp;ndash;is a form of the priestly office; and the nobility takes no delight in the priestly office (or priesthood).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/01/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/01/6/</guid>
      <description>01 [The Adhvaryu and Sacrificer whisper in the right ear of the horse, Vāj. S. XXII, 19 1,] &amp;lsquo;Plenteous by the mother, strengthful by the father,&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;its mother, doubtless, is this (earth), and its father yonder (sky): it is to these two he commits it;&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;a horse thou art, a steed thou art,&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;he thereby instructs it, whence clever subjects (or children) are born to him;&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;a courser (atya) thou art, a charger thou art,&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;he therewith leads it beyond (ati), whence the horse goes beyond (surpasses) other animals, and whence the horse attains to pre-eminence among animals;&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;a runner thou art, a racer thou art, a prize-winner thou art,&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;in accordance with the text is (the meaning of) this;&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;a male thou art, well-disposed towards man thou art,&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;this is with a view to its (or, his) being supplied with a mate;&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;Speedy thou art called, Child thou art called,&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;this is the horse&amp;rsquo;s favourite name: by its favourite name he thus addresses it; whence even if two enemies 2, on meeting together, address one another by name, they get on amicably together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/01/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/01/8/</guid>
      <description>01 Prajāpati poured forth the life-sap of the horse 1. When poured forth, it weighed down the r̥c (hymn-verse) and the sāman (hymn-tune). The Vaiśvadeva (offerings) upheld that (Aśvamedha): thus, when he offers the Vaiśvadevas, it is for the upholding of the Aśvamedha. 02 With (Vāj. S. XXII, 20), &amp;lsquo;To Ka hail! To the Who hail! To the Whoever hail!&amp;rsquo; he makes the one relating to Prajāpati the first (or chief one), and thus upholds (the Aśvamedha) by means of the deities with Prajāpati as their chief.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/01/9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/01/9/</guid>
      <description>01 [Vāj. S. XXII, 22 1], &amp;lsquo;In the priestly office (brahman) may the Brāhmaṇa be born, endowed with spiritual lustre (brahmavarcasa):&amp;rsquo; on the Brāhmaṇa he thereby bestows spiritual lustre, whence of old the Brāhmaṇa was born as one endowed with spiritual lustre 2. 02 &amp;lsquo;In the royal order may the Rājanya be born, heroic, skilled in archery, sure of his mark, and a mighty car-fighter:&amp;rsquo; on the Rājanya he thereby bestows the grandeur of heroism 3, whence of old the Rājanya was born as one heroic, skilled in archery, certain of his mark, and a mighty car-fighter.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
