<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०२ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/02/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०२ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/02/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>THE FIRST SOMA-DAY (AGNISHTOMA)xa0[^fn_743].</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/02/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/02/1/</guid>
      <description>01 Prajāpati assigned the sacrifices to the gods; the Aśvamedha he kept for himself. The gods said to him, &amp;lsquo;Surely, this&amp;ndash;to wit, the Aśvamedha&amp;ndash;is a sacrifice: let us have a share in that also.&amp;rsquo; He contrived these Anna-homas (food-oblations) for them: thus when he performs the Annahomas, it is the gods he thereby gratifies.
02 With ghee he makes offering, for ghee is fiery mettle: by means of fiery mettle he thus lays fiery mettle into him (the horse and Sacrificer).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE SECOND SOMA-DAY (UKTHYA).</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/02/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/02/2/</guid>
      <description>01 Verily, this&amp;ndash;to wit, the Aśvamedha&amp;ndash;is the king of sacrifices. But, indeed, the Aśvamedha is the Sacrificer, (for) the sacrifice is the Sacrificer: when he (the priest) binds victims to the horse (or, at the horse-sacrifice), he then, indeed, takes hold 1 of the sacrifice at the sacrifice. 02 &amp;lsquo;A horse, a hornless he-goat, and a Gomr̥ga 2&amp;rsquo; these they bind to the central stake: thereby, indeed, he (the priest) sharpens the front of his (the Sacrificer&amp;rsquo;s) army 3, whence the front of the king&amp;rsquo;s army is sure to become terrible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/02/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/02/10/</guid>
      <description>01 When they prepare the knife-paths, the Sacrificer makes for himself that passage across, a bridge, for the attainment of the heavenly world. 02 They prepare them by means of needles; the needles, doubtless, are the people 1 (clans), and the Aśvamedha is the royal power: they thus supply him with people and royal power combined. They are made of gold: the meaning of this has been explained. 03 Three kinds of needles are (used), copper ones, silver ones, and gold ones;&amp;ndash;those of copper, doubtless, are the (principal) regions (of the compass), those of silver the intermediate ones, and those of gold the upper ones: it is by means of these (regions) they render it fit and proper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/02/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/02/11/</guid>
      <description>01 Prajāpati desired, &amp;lsquo;Would that I were great, and more numerous!&amp;rsquo; He perceived those two Mahiman (greatness) cups of Soma at the Aśvamedha; he offered them; and thereby, indeed, became great and more numerous: hence whosoever should desire to become great, and more numerous, let him offer up those two Mahiman cups of Soma at the Aśvamedha; and he indeed becomes great and more numerous. 02 He offers them on both sides (before and after) the omentum;&amp;ndash;the Aśvamedha, doubtless, is the Sacrificer, and that Mahiman (cup) is the king: it is with royal dignity he thus encompasses him on both sides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/02/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/02/3/</guid>
      <description>01 Now, the gods did not know the Pavamāna 1 at the Aśvamedha to be the heavenly world, but the horse knew it. When, at the Aśvamedha, they glide along 2 with the horse for the Pavamāna (-stotra), it is for getting to know (the way to) the heavenly world; and they hold on to the horse&amp;rsquo;s tail, in order to reach the heavenly world; for man does not rightly know (the way to) the heavenly world, but the horse does rightly know it</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/02/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/02/4/</guid>
      <description>01 Prajāpati desired, &amp;lsquo;Would that I might gain both worlds, the world of the gods, and the world of men.&amp;rsquo; He saw those beasts, the tame and the wild ones; he seized them, and by means of them took possession of these two worlds: by means of the tame beasts he took possession of this (terrestrial) world, and by means of the wild beasts of yonder (world); for this world is the world of men, and yonder world is the world of the gods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/02/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/02/5/</guid>
      <description>01 Prajāpati poured forth the life-sap of the horse (aśva-medha); when poured forth it went from him. Having become fivefold 1 it entered the year, and they (the five parts) became those half-months 2. He followed it up by means of the fifteenfold (sets of victims 3), and found it; and having found it, he took possession of it by means of the fifteenfold ones; for, indeed, they&amp;ndash;to wit, the fifteenfold (sets)&amp;ndash;are a symbol of the half-months, and when he seizes the fifteenfold ones, it is the half-months the Sacrificer thereby takes possession of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/02/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/02/6/</guid>
      <description>01 [He puts the horse to the chariot 1 with Vāj. S. XXIII, 5], &amp;lsquo;They harness the ruddy bay, moving (round the moveless: the lights shine in the heavens);&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;the ruddy bay, doubtless, is yonder sun: it is yonder sun he harnesses for him, for the gaining of the heavenly world.
02 Concerning this they say, &amp;lsquo;Surely, the sacrifice goes from him whose beast, when brought up, goes elsewhere than the vedi (altar-ground).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/02/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/02/7/</guid>
      <description>01 When the victims have been bound (to the stakes), the Adhvaryu takes the sprinkling-water in order to sprinkle the horse. Whilst the Sacrificer holds on to him behind, he (in sprinkling the horse) runs rapidly through the formula used at the Soma-sacrifice 1, and then commences the one for the Aśvamedha. 02 [Vāj. S. XXIII, 13,] &amp;lsquo;May Vāyu favour thee with cooked kinds of food 2,&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;Vāyu (the wind) indeed cooks it 3;&amp;ndash;&amp;rsquo;the dark-necked one with he-goats,&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;the dark-necked one, doubtless, is Agni (the fire); and the fire indeed cooks it (the horse) together with the he-goats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/02/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/02/8/</guid>
      <description>01 Now the gods, when going upwards, did not know (the way to) the heavenly world, but the horse knew it: when they go upwards with the horse, it is in order to know (the way to) the heavenly world. &amp;lsquo;A cloth, an upper cloth, and gold,&amp;rsquo; this 1 is what they spread out for the horse 2: thereon they quiet (slay) it, as (is done) for no other victim; and thus they separate it from the other victims.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/02/9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/13/02/9/</guid>
      <description>01 But, indeed, that glory, royal power, passes away from him who performs the Aśvamedha. 02 [The Udgātr̥ 1 says concerning the king&amp;rsquo;s favourite wife, Vāj. S. XXIII, 26,] &amp;lsquo;Raise her upwards 2,&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;the Aśvamedha, doubtless, is that glory, royal power: that glory, royal power, he thus raises for him (the Sacrificer) upward. 03 &amp;lsquo;Even as one taking a burden up a mountain,&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;glory (pomp), doubtless, is the burden of royal power: that glory, royal power, he thus fastens on him (as a burden); but he also endows him with that glory, royal power.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
