<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०५ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/05/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०५ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/05/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>C. THE SÂKAMEDHA OFFERINGSxa0[^fn_909].</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/05/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/05/3/</guid>
      <description>01 Verily, by means of the Varuṇapraghāsāḥ Prajāpati delivered the creatures from Varuṇa&amp;rsquo;s noose; and those creatures of his were born without disease and blemish. Now with these Sākamedha offerings,&amp;ndash;therewith indeed the gods slew Vr̥tra, therewith they gained that supreme authority which they now wield; and so does he now therewith slay his wicked, spiteful enemy and gain the victory: this is why he performs these offerings in the fourth month (after the Varuṇapraghāsāḥ).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/05/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/05/2/</guid>
      <description>01 Now it was by means of the Vaiśvadeva that Prajāpati produced living beings. The beings produced by him ate (ghas) Varuṇa&amp;rsquo;s barley corn; for originally the barley belonged to Varuṇa. And from their eating Varuṇa&amp;rsquo;s barley corn the name Varuṇapraghāsāḥ (is derived). 02 Varuṇa seized them; and on being seized by Varuṇa, they became rent all over 1; and they lay and sat them down breathing in and breathing out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/05/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/05/4/</guid>
      <description>01 Verily, by means of the Great Oblation the gods slew Vr̥tra 1; by means of it they gained that supreme authority which they now wield; and so does he (the Sacrificer) thereby now slay his wicked, spiteful enemy, and gain the victory: this is why he performs this sacrifice. 02 The mode of its performance (is as follows): They raise an uttara-vedi 2; they use clotted butter 3; and they churn the fire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>V. THE KÂTURMÂSYÂNI  SEASONAL SACRIFICES.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/05/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/05/1/</guid>
      <description>01 Verily, in the beginning, Prajāpati alone existed here 1. He thought within himself, &amp;lsquo;How can I be propagated?&amp;rsquo; He toiled and practised austerities. He created living beings 2. The living beings created by him passed away: they are those birds. Now man is the nearest to Prajāpati; and man is two-footed: hence birds are two-footed. 02 Prajāpati thought within himself, &amp;lsquo;Even as formerly I was alone, so also am I now alone.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
