<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०३ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/03/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०३ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/03/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/03/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/03/1/</guid>
      <description>01 The Agnihotra, doubtless, is the Sun. It is because he rose in front (agre) of that offering 1, that the Agnihotra is the Sun. 02 When he offers in the evening after sunset, he does so thinking, &amp;lsquo;I will offer, while he is here, who is this (offering);&amp;rsquo; and when he offers in the morning before sunrise, he does so thinking, &amp;lsquo;I will offer, while he is here, who is this (offering):&amp;rsquo; and for this reason, they say, the Agnihotra is the Sun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/03/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/03/2/</guid>
      <description>01 Verily, in him that exists 1, these deities reside, to wit, Indra, king Yama, Naḍa the Naishadha 2 (king), Anaśnat Sāṅgamana, and Asat Pāṁsava. 02 Now Indra, in truth, is the same as the Āhavanīya; and king Yama is the same as the Gārhapatya; and Naḍa Naishadha is the same as the Anvāhāryapacana (Dakshiṇa fire); and because day by day they take that (fire) to the south, therefore indeed they say that day by day Naḍa Naishadha carries king Yama 3 (further) south.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/03/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/03/3/</guid>
      <description>01 Now when Prajāpati, in creating living beings, created Agni, the latter, as soon as born, sought to burn everything here: and so everybody tried to get out of his way 1. The creatures then existing sought to crush him. Being unable to endure this, he went to man. 02 He said, &amp;lsquo;I cannot endure this: come, let me enter into thee! Having reproduced me, maintain me; and as thou wilt reproduce and maintain me in this world, even so will I reproduce and maintain thee in yonder world!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/03/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/02/03/4/</guid>
      <description>01 Once on a time the gods deposited with Agni all their beasts, both domestic and wild; either because they were about to engage in battle or from a desire of free scope, or because they thought that he (Agni) would protect them as the best protector. 02 Now Agni coveted them, and seizing them he entered the night with them. &amp;lsquo;Let us go back thither,&amp;rsquo; said the gods, and betook themselves to where Agni was concealed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
