<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०२ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/02/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०२ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/02/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>B. THE RÂGASÛYA,  INAUGURATION OF A KING.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/02/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/02/3/</guid>
      <description>01 He offers a full-offering 1; for the full means the All: &amp;lsquo;May I be consecrated after encompassing the All!&amp;rsquo; thus he thinks. At this (offering) he bestows a boon; for a boon means all: &amp;lsquo;Having encompassed the All (the universe), may I be consecrated! thus he thinks. He may perform this offering, if he chooses; or, if he chooses, he may disregard it. 02 And on the following day he prepares a cake on eight potsherds, as sacrificial food for Anumati 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/02/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/02/1/</guid>
      <description>01 Thereupon, taking the clipping-spoon (sruva) and the pot for melting butter, he goes to the Āhavanīya fire. He either offers those twelve āptis 1, or makes (the Sacrificer) pronounce (the formulas). Whether he offers, or makes him pronounce (the formulas), the significance is the same.
02 He offers, with (Vāj. S. IX, 20), &amp;lsquo;To the ally, hail!&amp;ndash;To the good ally, hail!&amp;ndash;To the after-born, hail!&amp;ndash;To the purpose, hail!&amp;ndash;To the Vasu, hail!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/02/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/02/2/</guid>
      <description>01 He now proceeds with the Bārhaspatya pap. Its svishṭakr̥t remains yet unoffered, when he (the Adhvaryu) brings 1 him (the Sacrificer) some food; for he who offers the Vājapeya wins food, vājapeya being the same as anna-peya: thus whatever food he (the Sacrificer) has thereby gained, that he (the Adhvaryu) now brings to him. 02 In a vessel of udumbara wood&amp;ndash;the Udumbara tree being sustenance, (that is) food&amp;ndash;for the obtainment of sustenance, food: therefore it is in a vessel of udumbara wood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/02/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/02/4/</guid>
      <description>01 He offers the Vaiśvadeva 1 (All-gods’ offering); for by means of the Vaiśvadeva, Prajāpati created abundance (of food) and creatures, thinking, &amp;lsquo;May I be consecrated, after creating abundance and creatures!&amp;rsquo; And in like manner does this (Sacrificer) now, by the Vaiśvadeva, create abundance and creatures, thinking, &amp;lsquo;May I be consecrated, after creating abundance and creatures!&amp;rsquo; 02 He then offers the Varuṇapraghāsāḥ 2; for by means of the Varuṇapraghāsāḥ Prajāpati delivered the creatures from Varuṇa&amp;rsquo;s noose, and those creatures of his were produced healthy and faultless: &amp;lsquo;May I be consecrated for healthy, faultless creatures!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/02/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/02/5/</guid>
      <description>01 He prepares a cake on eleven potsherds for Agni and Vishṇu, a pap for Indra and Vishṇu, and either a cake on three potsherds, or a pap, for Vishṇu. He performs that Trishaṁyukta 1 offering. Therewith the gods came by men, and in like manner does this (king) now thereby come by men. 02 Now as to why there is that cake on eleven potsherds for Agni and Vishṇu;&amp;ndash;Agni is the giver, and men are Vishṇu&amp;rsquo;s: thus Agni, the giver, gives him (the king) men.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
