<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०१ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/14/01/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०१ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/14/01/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>THE MAKING OF THE POT.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/14/01/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/14/01/2/</guid>
      <description>01 He equips (the Mahāvīra) with its equipments;&amp;ndash;inasmuch as he equips it therewith from this and that quarter, that is the equipping nature of the equipments 1 (sambhāra): wheresoever anything of the sacrifice is inherent, therewith he equips it 2. 02 He gets ready a black antelope-skin,&amp;ndash;for the black antelope-skin is the sacrifice 3: it is at the sacrifice he thus prepares (the pot);&amp;ndash;with its hairy side (upwards),&amp;ndash;for the hairs are the metres: on the metres he thus prepares it;&amp;ndash;(spread out) on the left (north) side 4,&amp;ndash;for the north is the quarter of men;&amp;ndash;on (the skin) with its neck-part to the east 5, for that (tends) towards the gods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE PRAVARGYA.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/14/01/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/14/01/1/</guid>
      <description>01 The gods Agni, Indra, Soma, Makha, Vishṇu, and the Viśve Devāḥ, except the two Aśvins, performed a sacrificial session 1. 02 Their place of divine worship was Kurukshetra.. Therefore people say that Kurukshetra is the gods’ place of divine worship: hence wherever in Kurukshetra one settles there one thinks, &amp;lsquo;This is a place for divine worship;&amp;rsquo; for it was the gods’ place of divine worship. 03 They entered upon the session 2 thinking, &amp;lsquo;May we attain excellence!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/14/01/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/14/01/3/</guid>
      <description>01 Now at the time when he there 1 proceeds with the guest-meal, he who intends to perform the Pravargya, prior to the Upasads 2, spreads Kuśa grass with its tops directed towards the east, in front of the Gārhapatya, and places the vessels thereon in pairs 3,&amp;ndash;the Upayamanī (tray) and the Mahāvīra (pot), the pair of lifting-sticks 4, the two milking-bowls, the two Rauhiṇa-plates, the two offering spoons for the Rauhiṇa (cakes), and whatever other (implement) there is,&amp;ndash;these make ten, for the Virāj consists of ten syllables, and the sacrifice is Virāj: he thus makes this to be equal to the Virāj, the sacrifice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/14/01/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/14/01/4/</guid>
      <description>01 Now, when the Adhvaryu here steps up and says, &amp;lsquo;The Gharma is aglow,&amp;rsquo; they step up and revere it (the Mahāvīra) with the Avakāśa 1; but the &amp;lsquo;avakāśa&amp;rsquo; are the vital airs: it is thus the vital airs he lays into it. Six of them 2 step up to it, for six in number are these vital airs in the head: it is these he thus lays into it. 02 [Vāj.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
