<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०२ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/02/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०२ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/02/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/02/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/02/1/</guid>
      <description>01 The Śukra and Manthin (grahas), forsooth, are his eyes. Now the Śukra, indeed, is he that burns yonder (the sun); and because it burns there 1, therefore it is (called) Śukra (&amp;lsquo;bright&amp;rsquo;). And the Manthin, indeed, is the moon. 02 He mixes it with (barley) meal: thus he makes it to be gruel (mantha), whence it is (called) Manthin. Now those two (sun and moon); forsooth, are the eyes of these creatures; for were those two not to rise, these (creatures) could not distinguish even their own hands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/02/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/02/2/</guid>
      <description>01 The Āgrayaṇa graha, forsooth, is his self (body, trunk), and as such it is his all; for this self is one&amp;rsquo;s all. Therefore he draws it by means of this (earth), for of her is the bowl 1, and with a bowl he draws this (libation); and this (earth) is all, as this graha is all: hence he takes it by means of this (earth).
02 He draws it full; for the &amp;lsquo;full&amp;rsquo; means all, and this graha is all: therefore he draws it full.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/02/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/02/3/</guid>
      <description>01 That Ukthya (graha), forsooth, is his undefined breath (vital air) 1, and as such it is that self of his; for the undefined breath is the self; it is his vital energy. Hence he draws it by means of this (earth), because of her is the bowl, and he draws it with a bowl;&amp;ndash;for undecaying and immortal is this (earth), and undecaying and immortal is the vital energy; therefore he draws it by means of this (earth or bowl).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/02/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/02/4/</guid>
      <description>01 That (opening of) vital air of his which is in front, that, forsooth, is the Vaiśvānara (graha); and that which is behind is the Dhruva. Formerly, indeed, both these grahas, the Dhruva and Vaiśvānara, were drawn; and even now one of them is still drawn, to wit, the Dhruva 1. And if he acquire a knowledge of that (Vaiśvānara graha) either from the Karakas, or from anywhere else, let him pour it into the sacrificer&amp;rsquo;s cup; but this (Dhruva graha he pours) into the Hotr̥&amp;rsquo;s cup 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/02/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/04/02/5/</guid>
      <description>01 Having drawn the cups of Soma, and gone out (of the cart-shed to the high altar) 1, he offers the oblation of drops 2. The reason why he offers the oblation of drops is this. Whatever drops of that (Soma) are spilt here, to them he now wishes a safe journey to the Āhavanīya, for the Āhavanīya is the resting-place of offerings: this is why he offers the oblation of drops.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
