<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०४ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/04/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०४ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/04/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/04/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/04/1/</guid>
      <description>01 He recites after uttering (the syllable) &amp;lsquo;Hiṅ!&amp;rsquo; Sacrifice, they say, is not (performed) without the Sāman; and neither is the Sāman chanted without &amp;lsquo;Hiṅ&amp;rsquo; having been uttered. By his uttering &amp;lsquo;Hiṅ!&amp;rsquo; the peculiar nature (rūpam) of the word &amp;lsquo;Hiṅ&amp;rsquo; is produced (in the sacrifice); and by the sacred syllable (om) it assumes the nature of the Sāman. By uttering &amp;lsquo;Om! Om 1!&amp;rsquo; this his entire sacrifice becomes endowed with the Sāman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/04/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/04/2/</guid>
      <description>01 Now in former times the gods appointed Agni to the chief (office), namely, that of Hotr̥; and having appointed him to the chief (office) saying &amp;lsquo;do thou carry this our oblation!&amp;rsquo; they cheered him up, saying, &amp;lsquo;Surely, thou art vigorous; surely, thou art equal to this!&amp;rsquo; thereby endowing him with vigour, even as in our own days, when they appoint any one from among their kinsmen to the chief (office), they cheer him up saying &amp;lsquo;surely, thou art vigorous; surely, thou art equal to this!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/04/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/04/3/</guid>
      <description>01 The fire that has been kindled by means of the kindling verses, assuredly, blazes more brightly than any other fire; for, indeed, it is unassailable, unapproachable. 02 And in like manner as the fire blazes when kindled by means of the kindling verses, so also blazes the priest (brāhmaṇa) that knows and recites the kindling verses; for, indeed, he is unassailable, unapproachable. 03 He recites, &amp;lsquo;Pra vaḥ 1;&amp;rsquo; for the (word) prāṇa contains the syllable pra (&amp;lsquo;forwards;&amp;rsquo; or, is directed forwards):.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/04/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/04/4/</guid>
      <description>01 That same fire, then, they have kindled, (thinking), &amp;lsquo;In it, when kindled, we will sacrifice to the gods.&amp;rsquo; In it, indeed, he makes these two first oblations 1 to Mind and Speech (or, Voice); for mind and speech, when yoked together, convey the sacrifice to the gods. 02 Now, what is performed (with formulas, pronounced) in a low voice, by that the mind conveys the sacrifice to the gods; and what is performed (with formulas) distinctly uttered by speech, by that the speech conveys the sacrifice to the gods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/04/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/04/5/</guid>
      <description>01 When he (the Adhvaryu) is about to make the second libation with the offering-spoon (sruc), he (twice) lays his joined hands (añjali) on the ground before the two offering-spoons (juhū and upabhr̥t), with the formulas (Vāj. S. II, 7 b), &amp;lsquo;Adoration to the gods!&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;Svadhā to the fathers!&amp;rsquo; Thereby he propitiates the gods and the fathers, now that he is about to perform the duties of the sacrificial priest. With the formula, &amp;lsquo;May ye two be easy to manage for me!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
