<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०३ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/03/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०३ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/03/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>THE ABHISHEKANÎYAxa0[^fn_144], OR CONSECRATION CEREMONY.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/03/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/03/3/</guid>
      <description>01 He performs the initiation ceremony. On the day of preparation he seizes the victim for Agni and Soma. Having performed the offering of the omentum thereof; he prepares a cake on eleven potsherds for Agni and Soma 1. Thereupon the offerings of the Divine Quickeners (Devasū) are prepared.
02 For Savitr̥ Satyaprasava (of true impulse) he prepares a cake from fast-grown (plāśuka) rice 2, on either twelve, or eight, potsherds; for Savitr̥ is the impeller (prasavitr̥) of the gods: &amp;lsquo;May I be quickened 3, impelled by Savitr̥!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/03/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/03/1/</guid>
      <description>01 Having taken up both (the Gārhapatya and Āhavanīya) fires on the two kindling-sticks 1, he goes to the house of the Commander of the army, and prepares a cake on eight potsherds for Agni Anīkavat; for Agni is the head (anīka) of the gods, and the commander is the head of the army: hence for Agni Anīkavat. And he, the commander, assuredly is one of his (the king&amp;rsquo;s) jewels 2: it is for him that he is thereby consecrated (or quickened), and him he makes his own faithful (follower).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/03/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/03/2/</guid>
      <description>01 After the &amp;lsquo;jewels&amp;rsquo; he offers (a pap) to Soma and Rudra. It is cooked in milk from a white (cow) which has a white calf. And as to why, after the &amp;lsquo;jewels,&amp;rsquo; he offers (a pap) to Soma and Rudra. 02 Now, once upon a time, Svarbhānu, the Āsura, struck the sun with darkness, and stricken with darkness he did not shine 1. Soma and Rudra removed that darkness of his; and freed from evil he burns yonder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/03/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/03/4/</guid>
      <description>01 He collects (various kinds of) water. The reason why he collects water, is that&amp;ndash;water being vigour&amp;ndash;he thereby collects vigour, the essence of die waters. 02 In a vessel of udumbara wood,&amp;ndash;the udumbara (ficus glomerata) being sustenance, (that is) food&amp;mdash;for the obtainment of sustenance, food: hence in an udumbara vessel (he mixes the different liquids). 03 He first takes (water) 1 from the (river) Sarasvatī, with (Vāj. S. X, i), &amp;lsquo;The gods took honey-sweet water,&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;whereby he says, &amp;rsquo;the gods took water full of essence;&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;sapful, deemed king-quickening,&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;by &amp;lsquo;sapful&amp;rsquo; he means to say, &amp;lsquo;full of essence;&amp;rsquo; and by &amp;lsquo;deemed king-quickening&amp;rsquo; he means to say, &amp;lsquo;(water) which is recognised as king-quickening;&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;wherewith they anointed Mitra and Varuṇa,&amp;rsquo; for therewith they did anoint (sprinkle) Mitra and Varuṇa;&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;wherewith they guided Indra past his enemies,&amp;rsquo; for therewith they indeed guided Indra past the fiends, the Rakshas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/03/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/05/03/5/</guid>
      <description>01 He consecrates him at the midday Soma-feast. Now Prajāpati is that sacrifice which is here performed, and whence these creatures have been produced,&amp;ndash;and so they are even now produced after this one: he thus places him in the very middle of that Prajāpati, and consecrates him in the middle.
02 Before the Māhendra (cup) has been drawn,&amp;ndash;for that Māhendra cup is Indra&amp;rsquo;s special (nishkevalya) cup, and so is that Nishkevalya Stotra (hymn) and Nishkevalya Śastra (recitation); and the Sacrificer is Indra: he thus consecrates him&amp;ndash;in his own resting-place.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
