<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०३ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/07/03/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०३ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/07/03/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/07/03/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/07/03/1/</guid>
      <description>01 Built is the Gārhapatya, unbuilt the Āhavanīya; he then buys the king (Soma): the Gārhapatya being this (terrestrial) world, the Āhavanīya the sky, and Soma he that blows yonder, he thus places him (Vāyu, the wind) between these two worlds; and hence he blows between these two worlds. 02 And as to why he buys the king when the Gārhapatya is built, and the Āhavanīya unbuilt,&amp;ndash;Agni is the body, and Soma the vital air: he thus places the vital air in the middle of the body, and hence that vital air is in the middle of the body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/07/03/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/07/03/2/</guid>
      <description>01 Having smoothed (the sand) down with the two verses containing (the verb) &amp;rsquo;to grow,&amp;rsquo; and returned (to the hall) he proceeds with the guest offering. Having performed the guest offering, he proceeds with the Pravargya and the Upasad 1. Having performed the Pravargya and the Upasad, they appease that (first) layer on the (red ox-)skin. And as to why on a skin: for the obtainment of the forms, the skin being outward form;&amp;ndash;on the hairy side: for the obtainment of the forms, hair being outward form;&amp;ndash;on a ruddy (skin): for the obtainment of all forms, all forms (colours being contained) in the ruddy;&amp;ndash;on (the skin) of an ox: for the obtainment of Agni&amp;rsquo;s forms, the ox being the same as Agni;&amp;ndash;on (the skin spread) with the neck towards the east, for that (tends) godward.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
