<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०४ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/04/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०४ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/04/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>EXPIATORY CEREMONIES IN CONNECTION WITH THE AGNIHOTRA.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/04/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/04/1/</guid>
      <description>01 Verily, they who perform an Agnihotra enter upon a long sacrificial session:&amp;ndash;the Agnihotra, indeed, is a sacrificial session ensuring death in old age 1, for people are set free from it either by old age or by death. 02 Here, now, they say, &amp;lsquo;If either a team (yukta) were to drive through, or people were to walk to and fro, between the two fires of such a one performing an Agnihotra, and (being thus) a performer of a long session, what rite and what expiation would there be in that case?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/04/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/04/2/</guid>
      <description>01 They also say, &amp;lsquo;If any one&amp;rsquo;s Agnihotra-cow were to milk blood, what rite and what expiation would there be in that case?&amp;rsquo; Let him say &amp;lsquo;Disperse!&amp;rsquo; and having made a stirring-spoon, let him order the Anvāhārya-pacana fire to be enclosed; and having boiled that (blood) thereon, let him silently offer it in an undefined (indistinct) way 1, for Prajāpati is undefined, and the Agnihotra is sacred to Prajāpati; and the undefined also means everything: he thus makes atonement with everything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/04/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/04/3/</guid>
      <description>01 They also say, &amp;lsquo;If the fire were to go out after the first libation has been offered, what rite and what expiation would there be in that case?&amp;rsquo; Having thrown down (on the fire-place) any log of wood he may find lying near by 1, let him offer thereon, saying, &amp;lsquo;In every (piece of) wood there is a fire,&amp;rsquo; for, indeed, there is a fire in every (piece of) wood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/04/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/12/04/4/</guid>
      <description>01 And, in the morning, having taken out the ashes, and smeared (the fire-places) with cow-dung, he lifts the two fires on the churning-sticks, and returns (to the offering-ground). Having then churned out the Gārhapatya, taken out the Āhavanīya, and brought the Anvāhārya-pacana (to the southern hearth), he should prepare a cake on eight potsherds to Agni Pathikr̥t (the path-maker). The course of procedure thereof (is as follows):&amp;ndash;he should recite those same seventeen kindling-verses; the two butter-portions relate to the slaying of Vr̥tra 1; the saṁyājyās are two Virāj verses 1; and the invitatory and offering formulas are as follows:&amp;ndash;(the anuvākyā, R̥g-veda VI, 16, 3), &amp;lsquo;For thou, most wise Agni, divine disposer, readily knowest the ways and paths at sacrifices;&amp;rsquo; and the yājyā (R̥g-veda X, 2, 3), &amp;lsquo;We have entered upon the path of the gods to carry on what we can do: the wise Agni shall sacrifice, he shall be the priest, he shall order the sacrifices and their seasons;&amp;rsquo; for Agni is the path-maker, the guide of paths: he, verily, guides him upon the path of sacrifice.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
