<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०४ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/06/04/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०४ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/06/04/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/06/04/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/06/04/1/</guid>
      <description>01 He now digs it (the lump of clay) 1 up from that (hole);&amp;ndash;for the gods, having found him (Agni), then dug him up; and in like manner this one, after finding him, now digs him up,&amp;ndash;with (Vāj. S. XI, 28), &amp;lsquo;At the impulse of the god Savitr̥, by the arms of the Aśvins, by the hands of Pūshan, I dig thee, the Agni Purīshya, from the lap of the earth, Aṅgiras-like;&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;impelled by Savitr̥, he thus, by means of those deities, digs him up, the Agni favourable to cattle, as Agni (did).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/06/04/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/06/04/2/</guid>
      <description>01 He then touches the lump of clay, with (Vāj. S. XI, 32), &amp;lsquo;Thou art the Purīshya 1,&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;that is, &amp;lsquo;Thou art favourable to cattle; all-supporting,&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;for he (Agni) indeed supports everything here;&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;Atharvan was the first that kindled thee, O Agni!&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;Atharvan doubtless is the breath, and the breath indeed churned him out (produced him) at first: &amp;lsquo;Thou art that Agni who was produced at first,&amp;rsquo; this he means to say; and that same (Agni) he thus makes it (the lump) to be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/06/04/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/06/04/4/</guid>
      <description>01 That (lump of clay representing Agni) is still in his hand when he addresses the animals; for the gods, being about to equip 1 (Agni), now first laid vigour into them; and in like manner does this (Sacrificer, or priest) now, being about to equip (Agni), first lay vigour into these (cattle). 02 He addresses the horse, with (Vāj. S. XI, 43 R̥k S. X, 1, 2), &amp;lsquo;Thus born, art thou the child of the two worlds;&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;the two worlds, doubtless, are these two, heaven and earth; and he (Agni) thus born, is the child of these two;&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;O Agni, the lovely (child), distributed among the plants,&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;for he, the lovely one, is indeed distributed among all the plants 2;&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;a brilliant child, through gloom and night,&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;for as a brilliant child, he (Agni) indeed shines beyond gloom and night;&amp;ndash;&amp;lsquo;crying aloud thou didst go forth from the mothers;&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;his mothers, doubtless, are the plants, and from them he comes forth crying aloud.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
