<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०६ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/06/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०६ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/06/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/06/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/06/1/</guid>
      <description>01 Now at the house of Aruṇa Aupaveśi 1 these came once together,&amp;ndash;Satyayajña Paulushi, Mahāśāla Jābāla, Buḍila Āśvatarāśvi, Indradyumna Bhāllaveya, and Janaśārkarākshya. They took counsel together regarding (Agni) Vaiśvānara, but did not agree as to Vaiśvānara 2. 02 They said, &amp;lsquo;There is that Aśvapati Kaikeya who knows Vaiśvānara thoroughly 3: let us go to him!&amp;rsquo; They went to Aśvapati Kaikeya. He ordered for them separate dwellings, separate honours, separate Soma-sacrifices each with a thousand gifts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/06/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/06/2/</guid>
      <description>01 Now, indeed, there is this twofold thing, to wit, the eater and that which is eaten 1; and when this pair meets it is called the eater, and not the eaten. 02 Now that eater is the same as this Agni (the fire and fire-altar); and whatever they assign to him is his assignments; and these assignments (āhiti) are mystically called oblations (āhuti), for the gods love the mystic. 03 And the eater, doubtless, is the sun, and his assignments (offerings) are the moon, for the moon is assigned to the sun 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/06/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/06/3/</guid>
      <description>01 Let him meditate upon the &amp;rsquo;true Brahman.&amp;rsquo; Now, man here, indeed, is possessed of understanding 1, and according to how great his understanding is when he departs this world, so does he, on passing away, enter yonder world. 02 Let him meditate on the Self, which is made up of intelligence, and endowed with a body of spirit, with a form of light, and with an etherial nature, which changes its shape at will, is swift as thought, of true resolve, and true purpose, which consists of all sweet odours and tastes, which holds sway over all the regions and pervades this whole universe, which is speechless and indifferent 2;even as a grain of rice, or a grain of barley, or a grain of millet, or the smallest granule of millet, so is this golden 3 Purusha in the heart; even as a smokeless light, it is greater than the sky, greater than the ether, greater than the earth, greater than all existing things;&amp;ndash;that self of the spirit (breath) is my self: on passing away from hence I shall obtain that self.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/06/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/06/4/</guid>
      <description>01 Verily, the dawn is the head of the sacrificial horse 1, the sun its eye, the wind its breath, Agni Vaiśvānara (the fire belonging to all men) its open mouth. The year is the body of the sacrificial horse, the sky its back, the air its belly, the earth the under part of its belly, the quarters its flanks, the intermediate quarters its ribs, the seasons its limbs, the months and half-months its joints, the days and nights its feet, the stars its bones, the welkin its flesh, the sand its intestinal food, the rivers its bowels, the mountains its liver and lungs, the herbs and trees its hair, the rising sun the forepart, and the setting sun the hindpart of its body, the lightning its yawning, the thundering its whinnying, the raining its voiding urine, and speech its voice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/06/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/10/06/5/</guid>
      <description>01 Verily, there was nothing here in the beginning: by Death this (universe) was covered, by hunger, for Death is hunger. He created for himself this mind, thinking, &amp;lsquo;May I have a soul.&amp;rsquo; He went on worshipping. Whilst he was worshipping the waters were produced. &amp;lsquo;Verily, to me worshipping (arc) water (kam) has been produced,&amp;rsquo; thus (he thought): this, indeed, is the Arka-nature of the Arkya 1; and, verily, there is joy (kam) for him who thus knows the Arka-nature of the Arkya.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
