<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०७ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/07/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०७ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/07/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>OBLATION TO AGNI SVISHTAKRIT, [AND THE BRAHMAN&#39;S PORTIONS.]</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/07/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/07/3/</guid>
      <description>01 Now by means of the sacrifice the gods ascended to heaven. But the god who rules over the cattle was left behind here: hence they call him Vāstavya, for he was then left behind on the (sacrificial) site 1 (vāstu).
02 The gods went on worshipping and toiling with the same (sacrifice) by which they had ascended to heaven. Now the god who rules over the cattle, and who was left behind here,&amp;ndash; 03 He saw (what occurred, and said), &amp;lsquo;I have been left behind: they are excluding me from the sacrifice!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE CHIEF OFFERINGS.</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/07/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/07/2/</guid>
      <description>01 Verily, whoever exists, he, in being born, is born as (owing) a debt to the gods, to the R̥shis, to the fathers, and to men 1. 02 For, inasmuch as he is bound to sacrifice, for that reason he is born as (owing) a debt to the gods: hence when he sacrifices to them, when he makes offerings to them, he does this (in discharge of his debt) to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/07/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/07/1/</guid>
      <description>01 He (the Adhvaryu) drives the calves away (from the cows) with a parṇa branch 1. The reason why he drives the calves away with a parṇa branch is this. When the Gāyatrī flew towards Soma (the moon), a footless archer aiming at her while she was carrying him off, severed one of the feathers (parṇa) either of the Gāyatrī or of king Soma 2; and on falling down it became a parṇa (palāśa) tree; whence its name parṇa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/07/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/01/07/4/</guid>
      <description>01 Prajāpati conceived a passion for his own daughter,&amp;ndash;either the Sky or the Dawn 1. &amp;lsquo;May I pair with her!&amp;rsquo; thus (thinking) he united with her.
02 This, assuredly, was a sin in the eyes of the gods. &amp;lsquo;He who acts thus towards his own daughter, our sister, [commits a sin],&amp;rsquo; they thought. 03 The gods then said to this god who rules over the beasts (Rudra) 2, &amp;lsquo;This one, surely, commits a sin who acts thus towards his own daughter, our sister.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
