<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;०८ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/08/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;०८ on यजुर्वेदे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/08/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/08/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/08/1/</guid>
      <description>01 Thereupon the Hotr̥, having sat down on the Hotr̥&amp;rsquo;s seat whereon he sits down after being chosen 1, urges, and thus urged the Adhvaryu takes the two spoons.
02 They then proceed with the Āprī (verses). The reason why they proceed with the Āprīs is this. With his whole mind, with his whole self, forsooth, he who consecrates himself prepares and endeavours to prepare the sacrifice. His self is, as it were, emptied out; with those Āprīs they fill it again; and because they fill 2 it therewith, therefore they are called Āprī.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/08/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/08/2/</guid>
      <description>01 When he (the slaughterer) announces, &amp;lsquo;The victim has been quieted!&amp;rsquo; the Adhvaryu says, &amp;lsquo;Neshṭar, lead up the lady!&amp;rsquo; The Neshṭr̥ leads up the (sacrificer&amp;rsquo;s) wife bearing a vessel of water for washing the feet. 02 He makes her say (Vāg . S. VI, 12), &amp;lsquo;Homage be to thee, O wide-stretched!&amp;rsquo;&amp;ndash;the wide-stretched one, forsooth, is the sacrifice; for they stretch the sacrifice (over the sacrificial ground): hence the wide-stretched one is the sacrifice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/08/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/08/3/</guid>
      <description>01 For the same deity for which there is a victim, he subsequently prepares a sacrificial cake 1. The reason why he subsequently prepares a cake is this. Rice and barley, truly, are the sacrificial essence of all animals (victims) 2; with that same essence he now completes that (victim) and makes it whole. This is why he subsequently prepares a sacrificial cake. 02 And why he proceeds with that cake after performing (offering) with the omentum is this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/08/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/08/4/</guid>
      <description>01 Now there are three elevens at the animal offering,&amp;ndash;eleven fore-offerings, eleven after-offerings, and eleven by-offerings: ten fingers, ten toes, ten vital airs, and the out-breathing, in-breathing and through-breathing&amp;ndash;this much constitutes man, who is the highest of animals, after whom 1 are all animals. 02 Now they say,&amp;rsquo; What, then, is done at the sacrifice whereby the vital air is kindly to all the limbs?&amp;rsquo; 03 When he divides the hind-part into three portions,&amp;ndash;the hind-part being (an opening of the) vital air, and that (animal) extending from thence forward, that vital air pervades it all through.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNKNOWN_TITLE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/08/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/vedAH_yajuH/vAjasaneyam/mAdhyandinam/shatapatha-brAhmaNam/eggeling/03/08/5/</guid>
      <description>01 He makes the additional by-offerings:&amp;ndash;with &amp;lsquo;Go thou to the sacrifice 1, Hail!&amp;rsquo; The sacrifice is water, and seed is water: he thus casts seed. 02 &amp;lsquo;Go thou to Soma, Hail!&amp;rsquo; Soma is seed: he thus casts seed. 03 &amp;lsquo;Go thou to the heavenly ether, Hail!&amp;rsquo; The heavenly ether is water, and seed is water: he thus casts seed. 04 &amp;lsquo;Go thou to Agni Vaiśvānara, Hail!&amp;rsquo; Agni Vaiśvānara (&amp;lsquo;belonging to all men&amp;rsquo;) is this earth, and she is a safe resting-place: upon that safe resting-place he thus produces (creatures).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
